<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The free customes, benefits and priviledges of the copyhold tennants, of the mannors of Stepny and Hackny in the countie of Middlesex within this composition Before which is prefixed an abstract or briefe relation of the assurance given by the Right Honorable Thomas Lord Wentworth lord of both the said mannors, vnto his lordships said tennants (within this composition) for the ratifying and perpetuall establishing of the same. Whereunto two tables alphabeticall are fitted, the one containing the names of the said copyhold tenants, now hauing compounded: the other (with the marginall notes in the booke) serueth for the ready finding of any note worthy matter herein contained.</title>
            <title>Auncient severall customes, of the severall mannors of Stebbunhuth, and Hackney, 1587.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1617</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 162 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 48 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A73259</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 23254.5</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S125676</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99898390</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99898390</idno>
            <idno type="VID">135289</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A73259)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 135289)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 2051:17a)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The free customes, benefits and priviledges of the copyhold tennants, of the mannors of Stepny and Hackny in the countie of Middlesex within this composition Before which is prefixed an abstract or briefe relation of the assurance given by the Right Honorable Thomas Lord Wentworth lord of both the said mannors, vnto his lordships said tennants (within this composition) for the ratifying and perpetuall establishing of the same. Whereunto two tables alphabeticall are fitted, the one containing the names of the said copyhold tenants, now hauing compounded: the other (with the marginall notes in the booke) serueth for the ready finding of any note worthy matter herein contained.</title>
                  <title>Auncient severall customes, of the severall mannors of Stebbunhuth, and Hackney, 1587.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 70, 70-88 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by William Iones,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>At London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1617.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title on p. 1: An abstract of the indenture of covenants.</note>
                  <note>"Anno. 21. Jacobi regis." (caption title) has separate register; pagination is continuous.</note>
                  <note>Another edition, revised and enlarged, of "The auncient severall customes, of the severall mannors of Stebbunhuth, and Hackney, 1587", London, ca. 1610 (STC 23252); another issue of STC 23254, with additions: Memorandum, ... An acte for confirmationof the copyhold estates and customes ... of Stepny and Hackney.'--STC.</note>
                  <note>Text is continuous despite pagination.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library, London, England.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Hackney (London, England : Manor) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Stepney (London, England : Manor) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Manors --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <group>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <front>
               <div type="title_page">
                  <pb facs="tcp:135289:1"/>
                  <p>THE FREE CVSTOMES, BENEFITS AND PRIVI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>LEDGES OF THE COPYHOLD <hi>TENNANTS, OF THE MANNORS OF</hi> STEPNY AND HACKNY IN THE Countie of MIDDLESEX within this Compoſition.</p>
                  <p>BEFORE WHICH IS PREFIXED AN <hi>ABSTRACT OR BRIEFE RELATION OF</hi> THE ASSVRANCE GIVEN BY THE Right Honorable THOMAS Lord WENTWORTH Lord of both the ſaid Mannors, vnto his Lordſhips ſaid Tennants (within this Compoſition) for the ratifying and perpetuall eſtabliſhing <hi>of the ſame.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>Whereunto two Tables Alphabeticall are fitted, the <hi>one containing the names of the ſaid Copyhold Tenants,</hi> now hauing compounded: the other (with the marginall notes in the booke) ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ueth for the ready finding of any note worthy matter <hi>herein contamed.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <figure/>
                  <p>At London printed by <hi>William Iones.</hi> 1617.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="dedication">
                  <pb facs="tcp:135289:2"/>
                  <pb facs="tcp:135289:2"/>
                  <head>TO THE RIGHT HONORABLE THOMAS LORD WENTWORTH, Lord of the Mannors of STEPNY and HACKNY in the County <hi>of</hi> MIDDLESEX.</head>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>O whom Right (Honorable) ought we more iuſtly to dedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate this <hi>Collection</hi> of our <hi>Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes</hi> and <hi>Priuiledges,</hi> then vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to your good Lordſhip, the noble Patron thereof. The Clouds of Differences are now ouerblowne; euerlaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly may the bright Sun-ſhine of <hi>Peace</hi> beevpon theſe Mannors: That their Cuſtomes may be as famous, to the Right Honourable Family of the <hi>Wentworths,</hi> and ſought for to be Preſidents to o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, as were <hi>Solons</hi> lawes, which the <hi>Senate</hi> of <hi>Rome</hi> ſent Deputies to fetch (very neere foure hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred yeeres after the ſame had beene eſtabliſhed at <hi>Athens</hi>) thereby to frame their twelue Tables. Many happy yeeres (Right Honorable) accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany your Lordſhips life, vntill eternall Glory, ſhall make it perpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tually bleſſed.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your Honors moſt deuoted Tenants.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
            </front>
            <body>
               <div type="abstract">
                  <pb facs="tcp:135289:3"/>
                  <pb n="1" facs="tcp:135289:3"/>
                  <head>AN ABSTRACT OF THE INDENTVRE OF COVENANTS.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>HEREAS</hi> of late, Diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rences <note place="margin">The cauſe of the now com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounding.</note> haue ariſen, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tweene the Right Honora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble <hi>Thomas Lord Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth,</hi> Lord of the <hi>Mannors</hi> of <hi>Stepny</hi> and <hi>Hackny</hi> and his Lordſhips Copy-hold Tennants of the ſaid <hi>Mannors,</hi> for and concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning ſome of the cuſtomes benefits and priui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges of the ſaid Tennants. It hath now pleaſed the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> in conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration of three thouſand pounds of lawfull money of England, in the thirtieth yeere of the <note place="margin">The conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion giuen for it.</note> raigne of our late ſoueraigne Lady <hi>Q. Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth,</hi> by the Copyholders of the ſaid <hi>Mannors</hi> Vnto the Right Honorable <hi>Henry Lord Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth,</hi> his Lordſhips Father ſatiſfied and paid: As alſo of three thouſand and fiue hundred pounds more to him the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth</hi> 
                     <note place="margin">The Deede of Couenants.</note> now paid, by indenture bearing date the 20. day of <hi>Iune</hi> in the fifteenth yeere of the raigne of our ſoueraigne Lord King <hi>Iames</hi> of
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:135289:4"/> England France &amp; Ireland, &amp; of Scotland the fiftieth, made betweene him the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> Lord of the ſaid <hi>Mannors</hi> of the one part: And <hi>S<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Iohn Iolls</hi> Knight, &amp; diuers others of the Copyhold tenants of the ſaid <hi>Mannors</hi> (whoſe names are particularly in the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture recited) of the other part: For the ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peaſing and finall end of the ſaid differences, and for preuention of the like, and all other which in time to come might happen, ariſe or grow, betwixt the ſaid Lord his heyres or aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignes, Lords of the ſaid <hi>Mannors,</hi> and the ſaid Copyhold tennants their heires or aſſignes, to couenant grant conclude and fully agree to the effect following, that is to ſay,</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Imprimis,</hi> That the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> 
                     <note place="margin">That the Lord Thomas is ſeized in Fee.</note> is, &amp; vntill a perfect act of <hi>Parliament</hi> ſhalbe had and made, wherby all the liberties priuiledges, benefits, cuſtomes, immunities, diſcharges, additions, alterations, enlargements, matters, &amp; things, in the Schedules to the ſaid Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture annexed mentioned, ſhall be for euer con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed, ſhall bee and continue ſeiſed of a good, abſolute and indefeazable eſtate of Inheritance in Fee-ſimple to him and his heires for euer in poſſeſſion, of and in the ſaid <hi>Mannors</hi> and either of them, and of the Copyhold lands, tenements and hereditaments of the ſaid Copyhold te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants before mentioned parties to the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture. And that he now hath and then ſhall <note place="margin">And hath po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wer to confirme the following Articles.</note> haue full power and lawfull authoritie to rati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie confirme eſtabliſh and make good, All and
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:135289:4"/> ſingular the couenants, articles, alterations, enlargements, free cuſtomes, immunities, diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charges and agreements, contained in the ſaid Indenture and Schedules, or either of them to the ſaid Copyhold tenants reſpectiuely, and to their ſeuerall and reſpectiue heires &amp; aſſignes, of and in the ſeuerall and reſpectiue meſſuages, lands, tenements, and hereditaments, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of they are ſeized of any eſtate by copie of Court Roll.</p>
                  <p>And that the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> his <note place="margin">That theſe Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles ſhall for euer be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerued.</note> heyres and aſſignes, and all other Lords of the ſaid <hi>Mannors</hi> ſhall for euer hereafter, ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerue, performe, fulfill, allow, ratefie, make good and keepe all the ſaid Articles, certain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie of Fines, vſages, cuſtomes, priuiledges, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefits, immunities, diſcharges, compoſitions and agreements in the ſaid Indenture and Schedules contained: And ſhall not at any time hereafter, leauy, take, require, or demand any other fines, ſuites, cuſtomes, workes, or ſeruices, or in any other manner, then in the ſaid <hi>Schedules</hi> are ſpecified; And the Rents which for the ſaid Copyhold tenements by the ſpace of two yeeres now laſt paſt, haue beene yeelded and paid by the Copyhold tenants thereof. And alſo that the ſaid tenants, their heyres and aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignes ſhall for euer hereafter peaceably and quietly haue, hold, maintaine and enioy their ſeuerall and reſpectiue Copyholds, with their appurtenances, according to the ſeueral grants thereof to them made, and vnder the ſeuerall
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:135289:5"/> rents for the ſame reſpectiuely, now due and payable according to the true meaning of the ſaid Indenture and Schedules without any let, ſuit or hinderance, interruption, alteration, queſtion, or contradiction, whatſoeuer of him the ſaid <hi>Lo: Wentworth,</hi> his heyres or aſſignes, or any other claiming any eſtate, right, title, vſe, intereſt, office, profit, charge or demaund vnder his Lordſhip, his heyres or aſſignes, or vnder the ſaid <hi>Henry Lo: Wentworth</hi> deceaſed: And that the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> his heyres or <note place="margin">
                        <hi>That hereafter none of theſe lands ſhall be ſeuered from the Mannor. See A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ricle</hi> 68.</note> aſſignes hath not, nor hereafter ſhall grant, or conuey, ſeuered from the <hi>Mannor</hi> whereof, the ſame is now holden, any of the meſſuages, cottages, lands, tenements, or hereditaments of the ſaid Copyholders, for any other eſtate or terme, other then by copie of Court Roll, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the cuſtome of the ſaid <hi>Mannors,</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept the free-hold to be ſeuered at the deſire of ſuch perſon, as then ſhall be Copyholder there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of reſpectiuely. And that the certainty of Fines, free cuſtomes, immunities, liberties, priuiled<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, articles, diſcharges, and agreements in the ſaid Schedules contained, for and concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the ſeuerall meſſuages, cottages, lands, tenements and hereditaments, whereof the ſaid parties to the ſaid Indenture are Copyholders, or reputed Copyholders ſhall for euer be, and be had, vſed, accompted, adiudged, taken and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ioyed, as the true cuſtomes, vſuages, priuiled<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, immunities, diſcharges and liberties of and within the ſaid <hi>Mannors,</hi> and either of
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:135289:5"/> them, not to be violated, altered, changed, or denied by the <hi>Lord</hi> or <hi>Lords</hi> of the ſaid <hi>Mannors,</hi> or either of them now or hereafter, at any time or times in any wiſe being.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That for the better ratifyings, eſtabli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhing, <note place="margin">That a Decree ſhalbe had in Chauncery to confirme the now agreme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ts.</note> confirming, ſtrengthning, perfecting and making good of all and ſinguler the ſaid arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles, couenants, agreements, certaintie of fines, vſuages, cuſtomes, inlargements, and altera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions of vſuages and cuſtomes, compoſitions, liberties, priuiledges, freedomes, immunities, diſcharges, matters, and things in the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture and Schedules contained: and for the ſetting forth of what eſtate the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> is now, and then ſhall be ſeiſed of the ſaid <hi>Mannors</hi> and premiſſes, vpon a bill of complaint againſt his Lordſhip, in his Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties high Court of <hi>Chancerie</hi> to bee exhibited, his Lordſhip will appeare, and make ſuch an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwere, and further ſuch proceedings, that there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vpon a perfect decree with the free conſent and agreement of his Lordſhip may bee had and there enrolled againſt his Lordſhip, his heires and aſſignes. By which the ſaid Articles, co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uenants, agreements, certainty of fines, vſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ages and cuſtomes, and alterations of vſuages and cuſtomes and all the compoſitions, liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, priuiledges, freedomes, immunities, diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charges, matters, and things in the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture and Schedules, or any of them contai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned ſhall be decreed, ratified, eſtabliſhed, &amp; made good, and be put in vre: vſed &amp; enioyed for euer.</p>
                  <pb n="6" facs="tcp:135289:6"/>
                  <p> 
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That hee the ſaid <hi>Thomas Lo: Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth</hi> his heires and aſſignes, at his and their <note place="margin">That an act of Parliame<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>t ſhall be procu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to confirme the ſame for euer.</note> owne proper coſts and charges, will procure at the firſt Seſſion of the next <hi>Parliament</hi> of our Soueraigne Lord the Kings Maieſtie, his heires or ſucceſſors, one ſtatute or act of <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament.</hi> By force whereof the ſaid Articles, co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uenants, agreements, certaintie of fines, vſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ages, cuſtomes, enlargement and alterations of vſuages, cuſtomes, compoſitions, liberties, priuiledges, benefits, freedomes, immunities, diſcharges, matters and things in the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture and Schedules or either of them ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed, ſhall be eſtabliſhed, ratified, enacted, and confirmed to be, and to continue for euer, of force and to be put in vre and vſed for euer hereafter. in ſuch ſtate manner and forme, qualitie, condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and degree, as the ſame are in the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture or Schedules or any of them expreſſed, for and concerning the lands, tenements, and <note place="margin">The Tennants muſt pay twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty pounds to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the charge of i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</note> hereditaments, whereof they now are copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders, or reputed copyholders: Towards the charges of the procuring of which ſaid Act of Parliament, the ſaid tenants are to pay vnto the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth,</hi> his heires, or exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutors, within one month next after the obtai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning &amp; paſſing therof, the ſomme of 20. pounds.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That he the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> 
                     <note place="margin">For better aſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranc within fiue yeares.</note> his heires and aſſignes, at any time within fiue yeeres, next enſuing the date of the ſaid Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, before ſuch Act of <hi>Parliament</hi> as aforeſaid had and obtained, at the coſts in the law of the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:135289:6"/> ſaid Copyhold tenants, or ſome of them, vpon requeſt made vn<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o him the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth</hi> his heires or aſſignes, by the ſaid Sir <hi>Iohn Iolles, William Gough, Edmund Barber, Iohn Eglesfield, Iſack Cotton, Thomas Beſt, Richard Hoskins, George Saris, Henry Dethick, Iohn Howland, Thomas Yardley, Iohn Lowden, Richard Cheyny, Greſham Hoogan, William Palmer, Nicholas Dickens, Nicholas Diggins, Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Sumner, Iohn Bennet, Richard Edwards, Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chael Bonner,</hi> and <hi>Nicholas Hollam,</hi> or any ten of them, or any ten of the heires or aſſignes of them, ſhall and will make, doe, acknowledge, execute, and ſuffer all and euery ſuch further acts, deeds, and aſſurances, for better ſettling, aſſuring, and confirming of the vſuages, cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes, benefits, liberties, priuiledges immu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities, diſcharges, certaintie of Fines, compoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions agreements, matters, and things in the ſaid indenture and Schedules contained, as by them, or any ten of them, or any ten of the heires or aſſignes of them ſhall be reaſonably deuiſed, aduiſed, and required. <note place="margin">
                        <hi>That leaſes may be let for</hi> 31 <hi>yeeres and</hi> 4 <hi>months with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out liſence.</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That euery one of the ſaid Copihold tennants, their heires, and aſſignes, ſhall and may freely hereafter from time to time, graunt, leaſe, or demiſe, by deede, or otherwiſe, without <note place="margin">
                        <hi>See article.</hi> 38.</note> licence or copie of Court Roll, ſuch or ſo much of their ſaid lands, tenements, &amp; hereditaments, to ſuch perſon and perſons, and for ſuch terme and eſtate, not exceeding thirtie one yeeres and foure monethes, in poſſeſſion from the time of
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:135289:7"/> the making of any ſuch graunt, or demiſe, as to them and euery or any of them reſpectiuely, ſhal be thought fit or neceſſarie without any forfeite of eſtate, ſeizure, claime diſturbance, deniall, or impeachment of his Lordſhip, his heires or aſſignes, or any of his or their officers. So al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>waies, that ſuch graunt, leaſe, and leaſes ſo to be made, be at the firſt or ſecond generall Court (for the mannor whereof, the lands or tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments ſo happening to be granted, leaſed, or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>myſed are parcell) to bee holden next after the making thereof bee publiſhed in open court of that Mannor before the homage there, and a remembrance thereof to be required to be made in the Rolles of the ſaid Court, for the date terme, and quantitie of lands, cottages, or te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements ſo granted, leaſed or demiſed: Which remembrance of the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> couenanteth and granteth, for him his heyres and aſſignes: To and with the ſaid <hi>S<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Iohn Iolls</hi> and the reſt of the ſaid Copyhold tenants vpon the tender of a certainty therof in writing, to the Steward, or deputy Steward of that <hi>Mannor</hi> for the time then being, together with ſixe pence in money, for the entring thereof, ſhall be in the Court Rolls of that <hi>Mannor</hi> duely, and in conuenient time, and without delay enrolled, and a note thereof deliuered by the Steward, or his deputy, to the party ſo leaſing, or any for him, without any other conſideration, fee, or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward to be giuen or paide for the ſame. <note place="margin">Recitall of the Letters Pattens from the King to my Lord concernning the Freehold.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That whereas the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth</hi>
                     <pb n="9" facs="tcp:135289:7"/> by his Highneſſe letters pattents vnder the great Seale of England, dated the 19. day of Iuly, in the thirteenth yeere o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> his Maieſties raigne of England, &amp;c. and forty eight of Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land. Hath obtained licence to grant to ſuch of his Maieſties liege people as he ſhall thinke fit, meſſuages, cottages, lands, tenements, and hereditaments, parcell or reputed parcell of the ſaid <hi>Mannors; To hold</hi> to them their heires and aſſignes <hi>in free and common Socage</hi> reſpectiue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, of his ſaid Mannors of <hi>Stepny</hi> and <hi>Hackny,</hi> by ſuch and the ſame rents, and ſeruices, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther profits, as in the conueyances thereof ſhall be expreſſed, and not to hold of the King in <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pite,</hi> nor of any of his Maieſties <hi>Honors</hi> or <hi>Mannors</hi> in <hi>Knights ſeruice,</hi> as by the ſaid letters pattents more at large may appeare. Now if the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> ſhal not at the firſt <note place="margin">If the Act of Parliament be not Procured: then the Ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants vpon re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſt ſhalbe made Freehol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders.</note> Seſſion of the next Parliament, procure ſuch an act of Parliament to be good and effectuall in law for the purpoſes aforeſaid: Then his Lordſhip will at all times after the end of the ſaid firſt Seſſion of the next Parliament vpon reaſonable requeſt, and at the coſts of the ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants, (whom it ſhall concerne) their heires or aſſignes, make, doe, and execute, ſuch reaſona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble acts, deuiſes and aſſurances in the law, whereby the ſaid Copyholders, their heires or aſſignes reſpectiuely, ſhall hold and enioy their and euery of their ſaid copyhold, meſſuages, houſes, lands, tenements, cottages, and here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, with the like wayes, eaſements,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:135289:8"/> commons and commodities, as are thereto now belonging, or now therewith vſed or enioyed. And the free-hold and inheritance thereof, reſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pectiuely to them and to their reſpectiue heires and aſſignes for euer. To be holden of ſuch of the ſame <hi>Mannors,</hi> whereof the ſame is now hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den in free and common <hi>Socage;</hi> for and vnder the ſeuerall and reſpectiue yeerely rents for all ſeruices and demands, as they or any of them doe now ſeuerally and reſpectiuely pay for the ſame, as by them, or their councell learned ſhall be reaſonably deuiſed and required.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That the ſaid Copyhold tenants, their heires and aſſignes reſpectiuely, ſhall and may <note place="margin">For enioying the Common.</note> for euer hereafter, without any let, impediment, interruption, deniall, or contradiction of his Lordſhip, his heires or aſſignes, or any clai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming vnder the ſaid <hi>Henry Lo: Wentworth</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceaſed, not onely during the time they ſhall be Copyholders, but alſo afterwards when they ſhall haue obtained the free-hold and inheri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance of their ſeuerall and reſpectiue Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holds, peaceably hold and enioy, ſuch and the like common of paſture and in ſuch manner, in all the Commons, Maſts, and commonable places of the ſaid <hi>Mannors,</hi> as they or any of them heretofore, haue, had, vſed, held, taken, or enioyed, or might lawfully haue taken or en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ioyed. <note place="margin">The Tennants not compoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding are excep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted from al be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nefit hereby.</note> Neuertheleſſe it is agreed, that neither the ſaid Indenture and Schedules, nor any co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uenant therein contained ſhall in any wiſe ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend or enure to the benefit or aduantage of any
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:135289:8"/> other Copyhold tenants of the ſaid <hi>Mannors,</hi> o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther then the ſaid Copyhold tennants named parties to the ſaid Indentures, their heires and aſſignes, and that for ſuch and the ſame lands, tenements, cottages, and hereditaments, with <note place="margin">The enrolling of the deed.</note> the appurtenances onely, as they or any of them now hold, or claime to hold, by copie of Court Roll of the ſaid <hi>Mannors</hi> or one of them as by the ſaid Indenture (wherevnto relation be <note place="margin">And where it is left.</note> had) more plainely and at large appeareth.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Memorandum,</hi> That the ſaid Indenture of the twentieth of Iune, together with a dupli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate therof were acknowledged by the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> the 21. day of <hi>Iuly</hi> 1617. before <hi>Sir Mathew Carew</hi> Knight to be enrolled, and is enrolled in the <hi>Chauncerie</hi> accordingly. The one part of which Indentures is left in the cuſtody of the company of <hi>Goldſmiths</hi> in the Citie of <hi>London:</hi> And the other in the cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtody of the Brethren of the <hi>Trinitie houſe</hi> at <hi>Ratcliffe,</hi> In truſt and to the vſe of the ſaid Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold tenants named parties to the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dentures.</p>
                  <p>The ninth day of <hi>Iuly</hi> 1617. in the ſaid fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth <note place="margin">
                        <hi>A ſtatute of</hi> 12000. <hi>pound for performa<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce of couenants.</hi>
                     </note> yeare of his Maieſties raigne, to the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> acknowledged a Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute of the ſumme of twelue thouſand pounds of lawfull money of England, vnto <hi>Alexander Preſcot,</hi> and <hi>Iohn Gore, Aldermen, Thomas Iones,</hi> common Sergeant of London, <hi>Francis Fulner</hi> and <hi>Ceorge Whitemore</hi> Eſquires, and <hi>Robert Mildmay</hi> Grocer, In truſt for and to the vſe of
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:135289:9"/> the vſe of the Copyholders warned in the ſaid Indentures, and thereof is a defeſance by In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture <note place="margin">The Defea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſance.</note> dated the ſame day to this effect <hi>(viz.)</hi> That if the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> doe per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forme the couenants and agreements contained in the aforeſaid Indenture of the twentieth of <hi>Iune:</hi> Then the ſame Statute to be void, and that the ſaid Conuſees ſhall deliuer vp the ſame Statute to the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> his heyres, executors, adminiſtrators, or aſſignes, ſo ſoone as the ſaid act of <hi>Parliament</hi> ſhalbe pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cured, according to the intent and true meaning of the ſaid recited Indenture. To this end the <note place="margin">Where it is left.</note> ſaid Statute and Defeazance are left in the Chamber of the Citie of London, to be kept in ſuch ſort as that the ſaid Conuſees may haue the ſame to be deliuered according to their coue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant. And the Chamberlaine of the ſaid Citie hath charged himſelfe with the receipt thereof, by order of the Court of the Lord Mayor &amp; Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dermen, bearing date the two &amp; twentieth day of <hi>Iuly</hi> 1617. <hi>Leman Mayor, Fiſh Chamberlayne.</hi> In <hi>Trinitie Terme,</hi> in the ſaid fifteenth yeare of <note place="margin">The procee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dings in the Chauncery.</note> his Maieſties raigne to a Bill of complaint was by the Copyholders named parties to the the ſaid Indenture of the twentieth of <hi>Iune,</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibited againſt the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> in his Maieſties high Court of <hi>Chancerie,</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth</hi> did appeare, and by his anſwere confeſſed the contents of the ſaid bill to be true. Wherevpon a perfect <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree</hi> with the free conſent and agreement of the <note place="margin">The Decree.</note>
                     <pb n="13" facs="tcp:135289:9"/> ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth,</hi> bearing date the two and twentieth day of <hi>Iuly,</hi> in the ſaid fifteenth yeare of the raigne of our Soueraigne Lord King <hi>Iames</hi> was obtained. And by the ſame the ſaid free cuſtomes, orders, immunities, &amp;c. and all and whatſoeuer contained in the ſaid Indenture of the twentieth of <hi>Iune,</hi> and the Schedules vnto the ſame Indenture annexed, are for euer eſtabli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed and confirmed. The ſaid <hi>Decree</hi> is likewiſe there enrolled. The true copie of the ſaid Schedules followeth.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="schedules">
                  <pb n="14" facs="tcp:135289:10"/>
                  <p>14 <hi>SCHEDVLES containing the free Cuſtomes, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, Immunities, Diſcharges, Benefits and priui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges of the Mannors of Stepney alias Stebunhuth and Hackney in the County of Middleſex, agreed vnto the approued, allowed, and ratified, as well by the Right Honorable Thomas Lord Wentworth Lord of the ſaid Mannors, as alſo by his Lordſhips Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold, or cuſtomary Tennants or reputed Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holds or cuſtomary Tenants of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, named parties to the Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture whereunto thoſe Schedules are annexed. By which all and euery the ſame Copyholders or cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomarie Tenants, their and euery of their heyres and aſſignes, are to hold, vſe, and enioy, inherit, alien, demiſe, or diſpoſe all and euery or any the Lands, Meſſuages, Tenements, Cottages and He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, which they euery or any of them reſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pectiuely doe hold, claime, or enioy, by force or pretext of any grant heretofore made by the Copy of Court Roll of the ſaid Mannors or either of them, the day of the date of the ſaid Indentures, That is to ſay, the twentieth day of Iune in the yeeres of the raigne of our Soueraigne Lord Iames by the grace of God of England, France and Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land King, defender of the faith, &amp;c. the fifteenth and of Scotland the fiftieth.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>IN primis,</hi> by the cuſtomes of the ſaid Mannors <note place="margin">Theſe copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holds are of in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heritance held of the Lord by the rod accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the cuſt<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ome.</note> and either of them, all the Copyhold Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements &amp; Hereditaments, which the particular perſons, (named parties to the Indentures, wher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vnto
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:135289:10"/> theſe Schedules are annexed) doe hold or en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ioy, are, and (time whereof the contrarie hath not beene within the memory of man) haue beene Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold and cuſtomarie lands, tenements and he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments of inheritance, demiſed and demiſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble by copy of Court Roll of the Mannors a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, or one of them reſpectiuely, according to the cuſtomes of the Mannor whereof the ſame are holden; and all copies of Court Rolls of the ſame Mannors and either of them, by all the time afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, for the ſame lands, tenements, and heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, haue beene made, and ought to be made, to hold of the Lord by the Rod, according to the cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtome of the Mannor whereof the ſame is holden, by the rents and ſeruices therefore due and accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed. And all the ſaid lands, tenements, and hereditaments haue beene paſſed and are to paſſe and goe from ſuch perſons, as according to the contents of theſe Schedules, haue power and are <note place="margin">
                        <hi>How Surren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders are to be made. See further in the</hi> 19 <hi>article,</hi>
                     </note> enabled to make Surrenders, to any other perſon or perſons by way of Surrender to be made to the hands of the Lord, by the acceptance of the Ste<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward of the Mannor, or his Deputy, for the time being, in Court or out of Court; or by the accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance of the Reeue of the Mannor whereof the ſame are holden, or by his Deputy, within the ſame Mannor, or elſewhere, in preſence of ſixe cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomarie Tennants, or by any Headborough of ſome Towneſhip or Hambler within that Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor in preſence of ſixe cuſtomarie Tenants, in or out of the ſame Mannors; which Surrender or Surrenders haue beene, and ſhall and may be to
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:135289:11"/> the vſe of any perſon or perſons, and their heyres for euer in fee-ſimple, or any perſon or perſons in fee taile, or for life, or liues, with Remainders, or without Remainders, as lands may be aſſured by the courſe of the common lawes of this Realme, or elſe to the vſe of the laſt Will &amp; Teſtament of the Surrenderers or of any other perſons according to the intent and limitation of ſuch laſt Will and Teſtament.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> the rents of all the Tennants both Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders <note place="margin">2 <hi>Quitrents are to be paid year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly at Michell<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas.</hi>
                     </note> and Copy holders which hold any Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuages, Cottages, Lands, Tenements or Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them, are yearely payable only at the Feaſt of <hi>Saint Michael</hi> the Archangell to the Lord and his heires, the ſame to be collected by the Reeues of the ſaid Mannors (ſeuerally and reſpectiuely to be yearely choſen, as hereafter is expreſſed) or their Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties; And all and euery the ſaid cuſtomarie or Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold Tenants to pay the ſeueral yearely rents, now yeerely due and payable for their ſeuerall Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyholds: and if any of the ſaid Copyholds for which any interequit rent is now pa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d ſhall here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after come into ſeuerall hands, the rent thereof <note place="margin">An entire quit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent come into ſeuerall hands ſhalbe apporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned.</note> ſhall be then apportioned by the homage, at the Court of the Mannor whereof the ſame are hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den, and ſo much onely as by the homage ſhalbe appointed to be paid <hi>(prorata)</hi> ſhall be paid to the Lord for the time being.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> All and euery Copyhold Tenant of the <note place="margin">3 <hi>At what Courts Tennants are bound to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </hi>
                     </note> ſaid Mannors or either of them, which now be, or hereafter for the time being ſhalbe, ought to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:135289:11"/> yeerely at two generall Courts holden for the Mannor wherof his lands or Tenements are holden vpon warning, as hereafter followeth: And alſo ſo many of them at all other ſet or appointed Courts, ſet, appointed and kept for the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor wherof their lands are hold<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n vnder the num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>r of eighteene, as ſhall be for that purpoſe eſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally warned therevnto by the Reeue, or his ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent Deputy for the time being: And <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>he ſaid Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants ſhall there doe their ſuites, and ſeruices, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to their tenures, except they be eſſoined, li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſed or haue ſome other lawfull excuſe, vpon the paine hereafter following; which two generall Courts haue beene commonly kept, and are to be kept yearely the one of them on Tueſday, the ninth day after Eaſter day, and the other about the Feaſt of Saint <hi>Andrew</hi> the Apoſtle vpon rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable <note place="margin">The two gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall Courtes yearely held.</note> warning, That is to ſay, in the Churches and Chappels w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>thin the ſaid Mannors openly vpon the Sunday ſeuennight, or Sunday fort<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>night before the day of ſuch Court to be holden.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any of the Coppyhold or cuſtomarie <note place="margin">4 <hi>Tennants f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>il<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to appeare, and not eſſoy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned: or reaſon able excuſe: ſhalbe amerſed.</hi>
                     </note> Tennants of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them doe or ſhal make default of their appearance at any of the ſaid two generall Courts, to which their ſuites ſhall be due: Or if ſuch Copyhold Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants as ſhalbe eſpecially and lawfully warned to appeare at any of the ſaid ſet Cou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ts, in forme aforeſaid, yearely to bee holden doe make default (to which the ſaid ſuite<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s or ſhalbe due) and war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning openly giuen as aforeſaid of the day and place of the holding of the ſame generall Courts,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:135289:12"/> and vpon ſpeciall and lawfull warning to be giuen for the ſaid ſeuerall ſet or purchaſed Courts, that then they that ſhall ſo make default (except they be eſſoyned, or haue ſome other lawfull or reaſonable excuſe) ſhalbe amerced by the Homage of the ſaid Court to be taxed and affered, by two afferors of the ſaid Court, <hi>That is to ſay</hi> by two Tenants of the Homage, whereof the Steward of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, for the time being, hath alwaies vſed to chooſe, and ſhall chooſe one for the Lord, and the reſidue of the homage haue choſen, and hereafter ſhall chooſe the other.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any Tenant be ſummoned to apeare at <note place="margin">5 <hi>What the ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants are to be allowed at ſet Courts.</hi>
                     </note> any ſet Court, or Courts to bee holden within the ſaid Mannors, or in any of them, &amp; doth appeare vpon the ſaid Sommons, he ought, and is to haue for his paines foure pence, and his dinner, or eight pence and no dinner, which ought and is by the ſaid cuſtome to bee paid by ſuch perſon or perſons who ſhall be the cauſe that any ſuch Tenants doe appeare for his or their matter, ſo it be not any matter or cauſe that concerneth an enqu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>rie or pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſentment to be made onely concerning the Lord for the time being his heires or aſſignes.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Coppyhold Tennants of the ſaid <note place="margin">6 <hi>The like allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance for view. par<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>icions and and other ſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons.</hi>
                     </note> Mannors; and of either of them, ought to haue e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uery of them like allowance vpon euery view by them to be made, and vpon euery petition by them to be made, or vpon other Sommons to appeare betwixt Tenant and Tenant, when they bee ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed thereunto by precept from the Steward of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them for the
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:135289:12"/> being, or by his ſufficient Deputie.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The homage of the Court of the ſaid <note place="margin">7 <hi>How tennants may be righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted againſt en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>croachments, annoyances &amp;c.</hi>
                     </note> Mannors or of any of them, may appoint ſixe or ſeuen Tennants vpon any complaint to them made by any perſon or perſons being Tenants of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, in open Court, that hee or they bee wronged by any in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>croachment, or any other annoyance to their Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold Tenements, which Tenants ſhal after the ſaid Court view the ſame encroachment, annoy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance and impediment, or place whereo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> any ſuch complaint ſhall be made, and therevpon to preſent or notifie the ſame by a day to the Steward, or to the homage at the next generall court, that there may be ſet a paine or amerciament, or both for the ſame, by the Homage at the ſaid next court, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the qualitie of the offence.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Homage of either of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors <note place="margin">8 <hi>The Homage at euery gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall cou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>t is to preſent decea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed tennants.</hi>
                     </note> are to make preſentment at euery generall Court, to be holden for the ſaid Mannors, or for either of them, of all the cuſtomarie or copyhold Tenants that they ſhall know ſhall bee deceaſed after the Court then laſt paſt, at or any time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſaid court, whoſe deaths were not then found and preſented, and that held any copyhold or cuſtomarie or reputed copyhold or cuſtomarie Lands or Tenements of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them: And alſo as neere as they can pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent <note place="margin">With their lands &amp; heires.</note> what Lands euery of them dyed ſeized of, and of what eſtate, and when he dyed, and who is the next heire or heires to the ſame perſon or perſons ſo dying ſeized, and of what age or ages the ſaid
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:135289:13"/> heire or heyres ſhall then bee of, as neere as they can.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Homage likewiſe ought to preſent <note place="margin">9 <hi>Alſo they muſt preſent the deaths of Free-holders &amp;c.</hi>
                     </note> the deaths of the Free-holders, and when they dyed, and who be their next heyre or heyres, &amp; the ages of their heires which held any Lands or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, and the nature of their tenures, ſo neere as they can, to the intent the Lord may haue his re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liefe, which is but the value of one yeeres quitrent of the Tenements holden of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them by Socage tenure.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If the Homage at any of the ſaid Courts <note place="margin">10 <hi>What ſhall be donne, if the next heire be not knowne.</hi>
                     </note> of either of the ſaid Mannors ſhall not know who is next heyre or heyres to any of the ſaid cuſtoma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie Tenants ſo dying ſeized, when they ſhal make their preſentments, That then they ſhall make their preſentment ſo accordingly, and then vpon the ſaid preſentment at the next generall Court then after, the Steward of the ſaid Mannors of either of them, or his Deputy for the time being, within the ſaid preſentment ſhall ſo be made, ſhall cauſe a Proclamation to be made in open court to the intent euery ſuch heyre or heyres may haue knowledge to come and take vp the Lands and Tenements of his or their aunceſtors, and ſo the Steward or his Deputie ſhall cauſe a Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to bee made from generall Court to generall Court, vntill three open and publique Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions <note place="margin">Three Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mations ſhal be made in two yeares ſpace for the heire to take know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge &amp;c.</note> be made in full Court, at three ſeuerall gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall Courts, which generall courts by the ſaid cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtome are vſed to bee holden commonly one halfe
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:135289:13"/> yeere after another, or thereabouth: So that from the preſentment made by the ſaid Homage of the dying ſeized of the ſaid laſt Tenant, vnto the laſt proclamation, ſhal be fully two yeres: And if there ſhall come no heyre of the ſaid Lands or Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, nor any for him or them, before the end of the court next after the court, whereat the laſt of the ſaid three Proclamations ſhalbe made, to make his or their claime, and proue himſelfe or themſelues to the Homage of the ſaid Court, in ſuch ſort as they or the greater part of them ſhall allow of to be the next heyre or heyres of the whole bloud to the ſaid Tenant deceaſed, or to haue title to the Lands and Tenements, nor to ſhew and proue as aforeſaid who is or ought to bee next heyre or heyres of the whole bloud to the ſaid Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant deceaſed, or next heyre or heyres expectant vpon any eſtate determined; Then the Lord of <note place="margin">If none appeare the Lord may then ſeaſe the land.</note> the Mannor whereof the ſame Land is holden for the time being, ſhall and may after the next court next after the ſaid three Proclamations ſo to bee made, ſeize the Lands and Tenements which were the ſaid perſons ſo dying ſeized, whoſe next heyre or heyres, or ſuch as ſhall haue title there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vnto cannot be found, or ſhall not come and make his or their claime and proofe as aforeſaid; and the ſame Lord then to take the iſſues and profits <note place="margin">And keepe it vntill an heyre doe come.</note> thereof to his owne vſe vntill ſuch perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons come that ſhall proue him, or them next heire or heyres to the ſaid perſon or perſons ſo dying <note place="margin">If no heire com w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>thin three yeeres after the third proclama<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tion, the land</note> ſeized. And if none ſhall come in, within three yeeres next after the third and laſt Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:135289:14"/> made as aforeſaid, that ſhall and can conuey and proue him, or them to be next heyre or heyres of the whole bloud, or ſhew, or proue who is or ought to be next heyre or heyres, or to haue title as next in Remainder or Reuerſion as aforeſaid: <note place="margin">ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ll eſcheate to the Lord.</note> That then the ſaid Lands and Tenements bee forfeited or ſhall eſcheate vnto the Lord of the ſaid Mannor or Mannors for the time being. Except that if the ſaid Lands and Tenements, ſhall or ought immediately, to diſcend, remaine, reuert, or come to any woman Couert, or Infant within the age of one and twenty yeeres, or to any perſon or <note place="margin">1 <hi>Except woe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men couert ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron</hi> 2 <hi>Infants within age.</hi> 3 <hi>Priſoners.</hi> 4 <hi>Perſons non ſanae memoriae.</hi> 5 <hi>Perſons out of the Realme.</hi>
                     </note> perſons being in priſon, or any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons not of <hi>Sanae memoriae,</hi> or that ſhall not bee within the Realme at the time of the death of the ſaid laſt tenant dying ſo ſeized, or at the time of the firſt, ſecond or third Proclamation to be made as aforeſaid: That then in euery ſuch caſe, the Lord for the time being ſhall haue but the profits of the ſaid Lands and Tenements vntill ſuch perſons, or his, her, or their heire or heires, ſhall come and make their claime, So the ſaid claime be made by the ſaid woman or her heires within fiue yeeres <note place="margin">Fiue yeares.</note> next after the death of her ſaid huſband, or by her huſband and her ſelfe, during the time of her Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uerture. And by ſuch perſon being within age or his heires before he ſhall or ſhould accompliſh his full age of one and twentie yeeres, or within fiue yeeres then next after he ſhal or ſhould accompliſh his full age of one and twentie yeeres. And by the perſon of <hi>non ſanae memoriae,</hi> within fiue yeeres next after he ſhall recouer and become of <hi>Sanae me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moriae</hi>
                     <pb n="23" facs="tcp:135289:14"/> and by the heire of ſuch perſon of <hi>non ſanae memoriae</hi> within fiue yeeres next after the death of his ſaid Aunceſtor or before: And by the ſaid per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon that ſhall be ſo out of the Realme or his heires within fiue yeeres after he ſhall returne, or if hee ſhall not returne by his heires, within fiue yeeres after his death: and by the ſaid perſon or perſons in priſon within one whole yeere next after his <note place="margin">11 <hi>No dower for woemen: <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>or Courteſie of England for men.</hi>
                     </note> or their enlargement from ſuch impriſonment.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> In the ſaid Mannors or either of them women ought not to haue Dowers of any cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mary lands or tenements within the Mannors aforeſaid, nor in any of them, nor men to haue any eſtate as Tennants by the curteſie of England.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any ſhalbe ſeized of any cuſtomarie <note place="margin">12 <hi>Eſtates of inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritance ſhall diſcend accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to Gauel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kynde.</hi>
                     </note> lands or tenements holden of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them, of an eſtate of Inheritance, and ſhall haue two ſonnes, or three ſonnes, or more, or hauing no ſonnes, ſhal haue diuers daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, or hauing neither ſonnes, nor daughters ſhal haue diuers Collatterall heires in one neere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe of bloud, or that are to make their reſort, from thoſe that were of the ſame neereneſſe of bloud to the Tenant dying; They ſhall be all co-heires to their ſaid Father, Mother, or other Aunceſtor, touching the ſaid cuſtomary lands and tenements, according to the cuſtome of Gauelkinde.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any man or woman die ſeized as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid <note place="margin">13 <hi>Touching diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cents where the tennant left iſſue.</hi>
                     </note> of any cuſtomarie lands or tenements of any eſtate of Inheritance holden of the ſaid Mannors or of any of them, and ſhall haue iſſue two or three ſonnes or more, whereof one, or two, or more of
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:135289:15"/> them ſhall be married, and haue iſſue in the life of their Father or Mother, and ſhall die before his or their ſaid Father or Mother, or hauing no ſons ſhall haue diuers daughters, whereof one or more ſhall be married and haue iſſue, and dye in the life of the Father or Mother, That then the ſaid iſſue ſhall inherite, and be co-heire with the ſaid ſonne or ſonnes, daughter, or daughters that ſhall ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uiue his, her, or their ſaid Father or Mother that ſo ſhall die ſeized as is aforeſaid, whether the ſaid iſſue be male or female, according to the cuſtome of <hi>Gauelkinde.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any perſon or perſons die ſeized as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, <note place="margin">14 <hi>How lands ſhal diſcend to thoſe of the whole blood where the tennant left no iſſue.</hi>
                     </note> and ſhall leaue behinde him neither ſonne, nor daughter, then the next of his or their kinne, being of whole bloud, ſhalbe heire or heires to the ſaid perſo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> or perſons ſo dying ſeiſed, <hi>That is to ſay,</hi> his, her, or their brother or brothers, brother or bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers children, or childrens children, according to the cuſtome of <hi>Gauelkinde,</hi> and ſo forth as long as any of that iſſue ſhall be on liue, being of the whole bloud; and in default of ſuch iſſue the ſiſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, and ſiſters children, according to the cuſtome of <hi>Gauelkinde,</hi> and ſo forth ſo long as any iſſue ſhalbe on liue, and of the whole bloud, and for lack of ſuch iſſue, the Vncles and their iſſues being of the whole bloud, ſo long as any iſſue ſhalbe liuing. And in default of ſuch iſſue, the Aunts and their children, ſo long as any ſhalbe liuing of the whole bloud, and for lacke of ſuch iſſue the next of kinne of the whole bloud, according to the cuſtome of Gauelkinde.</p>
                  <pb n="25" facs="tcp:135289:15"/>
                  <p> 
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any perſon ſo dying ſeiſed as aforeſaid <note place="margin">15 <hi>Males et Fema<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>les of one ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter cannot ioyne to be co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heires.</hi>
                     </note> without iſſue of his body, and hauing diuers bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers of the whole bloud, whereof the one or ſome of them ſhall haue beene married, and ſhall haue iſſue. and after iſſue had ſhall die, before the ſaid brother dying ſeiſed as aforeſaid; That then the iſſues of the ſaid brother or brothers ſo dying be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore him that dyed ſeized as aforeſaid ſhall ioyne and be co heire with the brother or brothers that ſuruiueth the brother that ſo dyed ſeiſed, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, whether the ſaid iſſue be males or females: But males and females of one Venter cannot ioyne to be co-heires together, So that the courſe of diſcents is to bee obſerued by the ſaid cuſtome, according to the cuſtome and nature of lands in <hi>Gauelkinde.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Likewiſe ſhall the iſſue of the daughter <note place="margin">16 <hi>Touching diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cents.</hi>
                     </note> that ſhall die in the life of the Father or Mother be co-heire with the Aunt that liueth being of the whole bloud.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Likewiſe ſhal the Vncles and the Vncles <note place="margin">17 <hi>Diſcen<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>s.</hi>
                     </note> brothers children being of the whole bloud be co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heires together as aforeſaid.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Likewiſe ſhall the Aunts, and the Aunts <note place="margin">18 <hi>Diſcents.</hi>
                     </note> ſiſters children ioyne and bee co-heires as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, and ſo forth of all further degrees, of all Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laterall heires being of the whole bloud, which may conuey themſelues to bee any Cozens and heires of the whole bloud to any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons dying ſeized of any of the aforeſaid cuſtoma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie lands, or tenements, according to the cuſtome of <hi>Gauelkynde.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:135289:16"/>
                  <p> 
                     <hi>Item,</hi> By the cuſtome of the ſaid ſeuerall Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors <note place="margin">19 <hi>How Copyhol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders of inheri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance may Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render.</hi>
                     </note> euery copyholder of Inheritance in fee-ſim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, may Surrender his ſaid copyhold lands and tenements, or any part, or parcell thereof vnto the Lord to the vſe of any perſon or perſons, and to his and their heires for euer, or to his or their heires, of his or their bodies or any otherwiſe in <note place="margin">
                        <hi>See alſo in the firſt article. &amp; in the</hi> 20 21 <hi>&amp;c articles.</hi>
                     </note> taile, or for life or liues, or yeeres, or to any perſon or perſons, and his or their heires; To the intent the ſaid Copyhold Tennant may declare his laſt Will and Teſtament vpon the ſame Lands, and Tenements, or to any other vſe, or vſes, vnleſſe it be to any corporation or corporations, or bodies pollitique or corporate, and euery copyholder in taile, or for life, liues or yeeres, of either of the ſaid Mannors may in like manner by the cuſtomes of the ſaid Mannors, and of either of them Surren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der their Copyhold lands tenements or heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments or any part thereof, according to the nature of their eſtates ſo the ſame Surrender be made ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the cuſtome concerning Surrenders as afore in theſe preſents is ſpecified, or hereafter enſueth; And all the ſame perſons to whoſe vſe euery Surrender ſhalbe made, are to haue their copies made to hold of the Lord by the Rod, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the cuſtome of the Mannor, whereof they beene holden by the Rents and ſeruices therefore due and accuſtomed. Vpon euery of which Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>renders the Fine and Fines for the ſame hereafter expreſſed, is by the ſaid cuſtome to be paid, and to <note place="margin">
                        <hi>The fines muſt be entred into the Coppyes. See act<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>:</hi> 26.</note> be entered into the ſeueral copies, or the margents of them.</p>
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:135289:16"/>
                  <p> 
                     <hi>Item,</hi> By the cuſtome of the ſaid Mannors, and <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Surrenders ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken by the headborow or Reeue in pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of</hi> 6 <hi>ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nantes.</hi>
                     </note> of either of them, euery Surrender taken out of the Court by the Headborow, or Reeue, or his De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putie, and in the preſence of ſixe cuſtomarie Ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of the Mannor of which the ſaid lands or tenements Surrendred ſhalbe parcell witneſſing the ſame ſurrender of any perſon or perſons of his or their cuſtomarie Lands or tenements holden of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them, and being of the full age of one and twentie yeeres or vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards, (except women couert Baron, and ſuch as are not of perfect minde) to the vſe of any perſon or perſons, are and ought to bee as good, as if it were taken in open Court by the ſaid Steward of the Mannors or of either of them, ſo that ſuch ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render be by the Homage preſented as hereafter followeth.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Surrender by a woman couert Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron <note place="margin">21 <hi>Surren of wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man couert ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron, in extremi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie of ſikneſſe.</hi>
                     </note> being of the age of one and twentie yeeres made together with her huſband of the lands, te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements or hereditaments, whereof ſhe is ſeized or eſtated is, and ſhalbe a good Surrender of her lands, tenements, and hereditaments holden of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them the ſame Surrender being made in her extreamitie of ſick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes or likelihood of death by the acceptance of the Reeue of the Mannor whereof the lands and te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements ſo ſurrendred are parcell and his Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie or either of them in the preſence of ſixe cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marie tenants or by the acceptance, of the Head<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>borow in the preſence of ſixe cuſtomary Tenants, But if any ſuch woman Couert Baron ſo ſurren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dring,
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:135289:17"/> doe after that recouer her health, and do not at the next generall Court then following ratifie and confirme the fame, before the Steward or his Deputie in the preſence of the Homage: Then the ſame Surrender is, and ſhalbe voide, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Surrenders made by any woman couert Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron <note place="margin">All oth<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>r Surr: by woemen co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uert baron.</note> (except before the Steward of the Mannor or his Deputie, where ſhee ſhalbe ſoly examined, or in extreamitie of ſicknes as is aforeſaid are and ſhalbe voide.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> All Surrenders taken of women as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, <note place="margin">22 <hi>All Surrenders taken dy the Reeue or Head borough muſt be p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>eſented at the firſt or ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond next gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall court.</hi>
                     </note> or of men by the Reeue or his Deputie, or by a Headborough for the time being, and in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of ſixe cuſtomarie Tennants as aforeſaid ſhalbe and ought to be by the Homage preſented, at the firſt or ſecond next general court holden for the Mannor whereof the ſame is holden after the ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king thereof, or within one yeere and a day next after the taking of the ſame Surrender, if any ſuch generall Court be holden, within a yeere and a day next after the ſame Surrender ſo taken: Or elſe if no ſuch generall Court bee holden within a yeere and a day, then to be by the Homage preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted at the next generall Court to be holden for the ſame Mannor, next after the ſame yeere and day, is and ſhall bee a good Surrender as if the ſame had beene taken by the St<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ward or his Deputie of that Mannor or woman examined as aforeſaid in open court or otherwiſe, all Surrenders taken by the ſaid Reeue or his Deputie, or by a Headbo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough, <note place="margin">Or elſe they ſhalbe voide.</note> and in the preſence of ſixe tenants and not preſented by the ſaid Homage in manner &amp; forme
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:135289:17"/> aforeſaid are and ſhalbe voide: But when any <note place="margin">when Surr: to the vſe of the laſt will, muſt be preſented.</note> Surrender ſhall be made by any perſon to the vſe of his or her laſt Will and Teſtament, to the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent that he or ſhe may thereby or therevpon make &amp; declare his or her laſt Will &amp; Teſtament: That Surrender is to be preſented at the firſt or ſecond next generall Court of that Mannor happening next after the deceaſe of the partie ſo Surren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dring perfectly knowne and not before. But if the ſame be not at the firſt or ſecond court next after the death of the ſame partie preſented: Or if the ſame party hath before in his life time made any <note place="margin">Or elſe voyde.</note> other Surrender of the ſame Lands or tenements and the ſame to be preſented: Then the ſaid Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render to the vſe of ſuch laſt Will and Teſtament is and ſhalbe voide. <note place="margin">23 <hi>The homage muſt write Bil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>la vera vpon their preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments &amp; good Surrend</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Homage muſt write <hi>Billa vera</hi> vpon euery Surrender by them preſented when they finde the ſame Surrenders agreeable to the cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtome, and alſo vpon euery other of their preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments ſhall make <hi>Billa vera</hi> when they bee agree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to the ſaid cuſtome: Or elſe if the ſaid Homage receiue any Surrender or other bills to them ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibited, which be doubtfull or repugnant to the cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtome of the Mannor whereof the land is holden vpon euery ſuch Surrender or <hi>Bill Ignoramus</hi> ſhalbe made, or the like ſuperſcription to the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent <note place="margin">And Ignoramus on the contrary</note> it may be knowne to be doubtfull or naught or elſe returne the ſame naughtie Surrenders or Bills backe againe to the parties that exhibited the ſame. <note place="margin">24 <hi>Woemen co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uert baron may turrender with heire huſbands &amp;c.</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Euery woman being Couert Baron of
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:135289:18"/> the age of one and twentie yeeres or vpwards, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing any cuſtomarie lands or tenements to her, or her heires or for life, liues, or yeeres, and holden of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them, may toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with her huſband by the hands of the ſaid Steward, or his ſufficient Deputie Surrender all her ſaid Lands and Tenements, intereſt and terme of yeeres to the vſe of her ſaid huſband, or to any other perſon or perſons, at their will and <note place="margin">Soly examined before the Steeward or deputie.</note> pleaſure: So as ſhe be ſolie and ſecretly examined before the Steward or his ſufficient Deputie.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> All Surrenders taken out of the Court by the Steward of the ſaid Mannors, or of any of <note place="margin">25 <hi>Surrenders ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken out of court by the Steward or his deputie.</hi>
                     </note> them, or his ſufficient Deputy of any perſon or perſons, being of the full age of one and twentie yeeres or more, and of <hi>Sanae memoriae</hi> of any of their cuſtomarie lands, and tenements holden of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, be good by the cuſtomes of the ſaid Mannors, and of either of <note place="margin">Muſt be preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted at the next generall courte.</note> them, and the ſame ought to be publiſhed and no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tified to the Homage at the next generall Court; Or elſe thoſe Surrenders are alſo voide.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> All the Fines vpon admittances, for any <note place="margin">26 <hi>The fines are certaine and not arbitrarie.</hi>
                     </note> the now lands, tenements, or hereditaments, of all and euery the perſons named parties to the ſaid Indenture holden by copie of Court Roll, are and ought to be certaine, and not arbitrarie or at the will of the Lord. And the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, ought to haue and take Fines vpon admittances, as hereafter <note place="margin">What fines are due.</note> followeth, and not other or greater, <hi>That is to ſay,</hi> vpon the admiſſion of the heire or heires after a
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:135289:18"/> diſcent, for euery acre of land of what nature or kinde ſo euer ſixteene pence, and ſo after that rate for greater or leſſer quantities of Land. And vpon admiſſion of one perſon onely after any Surren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the like ſomme of ſixteene pence for euery acre, and ſo after that rate for euery greater or leſſer quantitie of land; But if more then one perſon be admitted after or vpon any Surrender: Then <note place="margin">If more then one Perſon be admitted then &amp;c.</note> euery of the ſame perſons are to pay halfe ſo much as one perſon ought to pay and not more. Like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe vpon admiſſion of the heire or heires, after a diſcent for euery Meſſuage cuſtomarie, with the Courts, Yards, Eaſements, Orchards, and Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens therevnto belonging, for a Fine the ſomme of thirteene ſhillings foure pence, and not more. And for a dwelling houſe called a Tenement, with the Courts, Yards, Orchards, Eaſements and Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens therevnto belonging, the ſomme of ten ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, and not more: and for a cottage vſed for dwelling, with eaſements and gardens therevnto belonging, or without garden, and not demiſed for more then three pounds by the yeere, the ſomme of twenty pence: But for a building not vſed for a dwelling houſe ſo much onely as according to the quantitie of the land after the rate of ſixteene <note place="margin">What fine for a building not v<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed for a dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling houſe.</note> pence the acre: And for greater cottages vſed for dwelling, and which ſhall be let for aboue three pounds by the yeere, with the Courts, Yards, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chards, Gardens, and Eaſements therevnto be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing, the ſomme of ten ſhillings. And the like is of Meſſuages, Tenements, and Cottages here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after to be built: And vpon or after any Surren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:135289:19"/> at the admiſſion the like Fines are to be paide for one perſon. But if any Surrender be made by <note place="margin">Admisſion of man and wife, a whole fine.</note> any perſon, or perſons, to a man and his wife, then a whole fine is to be paid for the huſband, and halfe a fine is to be paide for the wife: And if more per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons be admitted vpon one Surrender, then euery of the ſame perſons are to pay for Fine halfe ſo much, as one perſon ought to pay, and not more. All acres are to bee acco<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>pted according to the ſtatute or ordinance <hi>de terris menſurandis,</hi> and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chards and gardens not belonging to ſuch Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuages, Tenements or Cottages, are to pay as lands according to the quantitie thereof, according to the rate aforeſaid. And parts of Meſſuages, <note place="margin">
                        <hi>The fines muſt be entred in the margent of the coppies. ſee article</hi> 19.</note> parts of Tenements, and parts of Cottages are to pay for Fines reſpectiuely, in regard of the whole, according to the rate of the whole. And all fines paid are to be ſet downe and expreſſed in the copie of the Court Roll thereof, or in the margent of the ſame copie. And if any queſtion or doubt ſhall hereafter ariſe, about the diſcerning and true eſtimation, what or which be, or ought to bee ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compted a Meſſuage, and what, or which a dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling houſe called atenement, and what or which a Cottage; The ſame is to bee referred to the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage of the Mannor at the next generall Court, and by the ſame to be tryed. ordered, determined, and preſented, &amp; according to ſuch preſentments, fines are to be paid. <note place="margin">27 <hi>The Lord is to allowe of all Surr: made ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to thes articles.</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Lord or Lords of the ſaid Mannors or either of them, and their and euery of their Ste<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards for the time being ſhall and ought to accept
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:135289:19"/> and allow of all and euery Surrender and Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>renders to be made of any the lands, tenements, or hereditaments, whereof any of the perſons na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med parties to the ſaid Indenture, are ſeiſed as co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py holders, according to the tenour, intent and true meaning of theſe Schedules, and the Articles therein contained. So as the parties Surrende<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring, be not before that time by the Homage of the ſame Mannor preſented, and found to haue made or committed ſome matter of forfeiture of thoſe lands and tenements ſo Surrendred, contrarie to the cuſtomes and articles in theſe Schedules ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed, or ſome or one of them. And the Lord of the ſame Mannor by his Steward for ſuch fine as in or for ſuch things is before expreſſed ſhal grant the ſame copyhold Lands Tenements and here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments ſo Surrendred, according to the tenor vſe and intent of the ſame Surrender. And ſhall duely admit ſuch perſon or perſons to whom, or to whoſe vſe, ſuch Surrenders ſhalbe made.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, <note place="margin">28 <hi>If the Lord re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to admi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap> then &amp;c.</hi>
                     </note> or either of them, or his or their Steward for the time being ſhall refuſe to admit any perſon or perſons, to whom or to whoſe vſe ſuch Surren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der. as in the precedent Article is expreſſed ſhalbe made, or ſhall refuſe to admit ſuch perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, to whom any of the ſaid copyhold, or cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marie, or reputed copyhold, or cuſtomarie, lands, tenements, or hereditaments, ſhall diſcend accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the cuſtome of the ſaid Mannors, and true meaning of theſe Schedules. Then the perſon ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> not admitted paying or tendering to the Lord or
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:135289:20"/> his Reeue, fine or fines for the ſame, according to the true meaning of theſe Schedules, ſhall and may into ſuch Lands, Tenements or Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments ſo ſurrendred, or diſcended reſpectiuely en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and the ſame quietly haue, hold and enioy as freely and in ſuch ſort as if he or they had beene therevnto lawfully admitted, and not otherwiſe.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any man make a Surrender onely to <note place="margin">29 <hi>Surren: to make the wife a ioinc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture</hi>
                     </note> the intent to make his wife a ioynture, or to aſſure it to his wife for terme of her life, or during her widdowhood, not altering the eſtate of the Inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritance, then for the fine of the ſame, or any admit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance therevpon, there ſhalbe paid but halfe a fine for the ſame, things ſo Surrendred; <hi>That is to ſay,</hi> halfe ſo much as one perſon ſhould pay vpon admittance, according to the true meaning of theſe Schedules: And the like is to be vſed where the huſband and wife make a Surrender of the lands of the wife, to the end only to make an eſtate there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to the huſband ioyntly with his wife, or to the huſband for terme of his life in poſſeſſion or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder: And likewiſe by the ſaid cuſtome for eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Tenant that ſhalbe admitted in Reuerſion, or Remainder expectant vpon the eſtate of any parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culer Tenant for life, in taile, or for yeeres, gran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by copie, the ſame is but halfe ſo much as it is vpon other admittances, vpon alienations, Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>renders, or dying ſeized as aforeſaid.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Euery perſon that exhibiteth or deliue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reth <note place="margin">30 <hi>Duties to the homage and tennants for billes and Su<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>:</hi>
                     </note> any Surrender or Bill to the Homage, ought to giue and pay to the ſame Homage for euery ſuch Surrender or Bill foure pence; and euery of the
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:135289:20"/> ſaid ſixe Tenants, and alſo the Hradborough or Reeue which ſhalbe at the taking of any Surren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders as aforeſaid ought to haue foure pence a peece of the parties that make the Surrender, if the ſame Surrender bee taken within the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, or in either of them. But if they goe out of the ſaid Mannors or either of them for the taking of the ſame, then to haue eight pence a peece, and their charges if they ſhall goe further off. And the partie that procureth the ſaid Surrender ought to giue to the ſaid Tennants foure pence beſides the ſaid fees, which foure pence is to be deliuered with the ſaid Surrender, or elſe he that bringeth in the ſaid Surrender without the ſaid foure pence, ſhall pay it of his owne purſe to the Homage.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If it chance at any time vpon the death of <note place="margin">31 <hi>Though an heire be admit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted yet vppon a new claime the homage ſhall enquire &amp;c. for a coheire.</hi>
                     </note> any Copyholder or cuſtomarie Tenant, that there is an heire or heires found and preſented by the Homage, and after is or are admitted to the lands or tenements of the ſaid Copyholder, and at that time no other heires ſhalbe knowne, and after it ſhall chance that one or other commeth, and clai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meth to be co-heire with the ſaid heire that is ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted, then the homage ought thereof to enquire, and if they finde his claime true, they ought to preſent the ſame, and then hee or they ſo claiming ſhall be likewiſe admitted and pay his Fine, and haue his part of the premiſſes notwithſtanding the former admiſſion.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any man be admitted to any poſſeſſion, <note place="margin">32 <hi>Wher tennan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>s is admitted, and after that an o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther claimeth the whole, the Homage is not bound to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire but he is driven to his fuite.</hi>
                     </note> or to any Reuerſion, or Remainder of any Lands or Tenements, whether they be to him diſcended
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:135289:21"/> as ſhalbe ſuppoſed or to him Surrendred by any other perſon, and after that commeth another per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons who pretendeth a title to the whole premiſſes, or to any part thereof, and deſireth that the Homage may enquire thereof. In this caſe the ſaid Homage is not bound thereof to enquire, but he or they are driuen to his or their ſuite or plaint, whether his or their title be right or wrong Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceptin ſuch caſe where any perſon or perſons ſhall claime as in the next precedent Article. And yet if any ſhall require the Homage to finde whether he or they were the ſonne or ſonnes or daughter or daughters of ſuch a one or no, &amp; the homage know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or well informed of the truth, that he or they ſhal be the ſonne, or ſons or daughter or daughters of him or her that dyed ſeized of the lands then in queſtion. The Homage ought therein to preſent the truth But not to preſent whether he or they ought to haue the premiſſes or any part thereof to the which another perſon is already admitted. But in ſuch caſe he or they ſhalbe driuen to his or their ſuite or plaint as aforeſaid for the recouery of their ſaid right if any right they haue; Except in ſuch caſe where any perſon or perſons ſhall claime as in the next precedent Article.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> After the death of euery perſon being a <note place="margin">33 <hi>How lands diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cended are to be taken vp.</hi>
                     </note> cuſtomarie Tennant of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, the next heire or heires ought to come and take vp the Lands and Tenements whereof his or their aunceſtors ſo ſhall die ſei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed <note place="margin">At foureteene <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>es he is to be admitted in his owne per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon.</note> of what age ſoeuer he be of. And if he or they be of the age of foureteene yeeres or vpwards hee is
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:135289:21"/> to be admitted in his owne perſon within a conue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient <note place="margin">At foureteene yeeres is to be admitted in his owne perſon.</note> time after hee or they ſhalbe preſented: Or elſe if hee or they bee vnder the age of fourteene yeeres, then to come and take it vp by his Gardian <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Vnder</hi> 14. <hi>yeres by Gardian.</hi>
                     </note> vntill he be of the age of fourteene yeeres as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, and to pay for his fine according to the rates expreſſed in theſe Schedules, and the Gardean to <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Gardian</hi> 3 <hi>ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ngs</hi> 4 <hi>pence.</hi>
                     </note> pay but three ſhillings and foure pence at the moſt for his fine for the Gardeanſhip or leſſe, as the Steward or his Deputy ſhall thinke fit. And for Lands diſcended from the part of the Father, the <note place="margin">Who ſhalbe Gardian.</note> next Cozen of the part on the Mother not able to inherite thoſe lands, ought to be Gardean. And if <note place="margin">
                        <hi>See ariicle.</hi> 37.</note> the lands came from the part of the mother, then the like coſen of the part of the Father ought to bee Gardean if that perſon will accept thereof; and vpon their refuſall or not praying to bee admitted Gardean, at the firſt or ſecond Court after that in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fant ought to be admitted; then may the Steward admit any other of the kindred of the Infant to whom his Lands cannot diſcend to bee Gardian. And if none of the kindred will accept of the Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dianſhip, then may another be admitted. And eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry <note place="margin">The Gardian ſhall accompt.</note> Gardian ſhall accompt to the heire of the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits, and repaire the Copyhold Tenements of him whoſe Gardian hee is, And vpon admittance ſhall be bound to the Lord for the time being, with <note place="margin">And ſhalbe bound to the Lord to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forme the ſame</note> condition for performance thereof in ſuch ſumme as the Homage of the ſaid Court, or the greater part therof ſhal like off. And of the lands of euery Infant vnder fourteene yeeres of age that ſhalbe a purchaſor a gardian ſhalbe admitted and ſhall ſo
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:135289:22"/> demeane himſelfe in ſuch manner as for the Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian of an Infant hauing Lands by diſcent is li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted and appointed.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Euery perſon to whoſe vſe any of the ſaid <note place="margin">34 <hi>They to whoſe vſe Lands are ſurrendred, ought within</hi> 3. <hi>yeares after the preſentment to take them vp.</hi>
                     </note> Lands or Tenements ſhalbe Surrendred ought to come within three yeeres after the ſame bee pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented and take vp the ſame by himſelfe if he be of age, and to be admitted as aforeſaid, and to pay his fine or elſe by his Gardian as aforeſaid.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any of the ſaid heires, Alienees, or Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dians <note place="margin">35 <hi>The Lord may diſtraine for the Fines. Or by de fault of diſtreſe ſelfe the lands.</hi>
                     </note> doe not pay their Fines within one moneth after the ſame fines be extracted, and the extracts deliuered to the Reeue or his Deputie for the ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thering thereof, and by them or either of them de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded, then it ſhall bee lawfull for the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Mannor or Mannors for the time being, or his or their officers to diſtraine; and auow as for rents, and for want of diſtreſſe to ſeize the Lands and Tenements for the which the ſaid fine or fines are to be paid, and to enioy the ſame to his or their owne vſe, vntill he or they ſhalbe ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſatiſfied and paid the ſaid Fine or Fines to bee paid by him or them that ſo ought to pay the ſame.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any cuſtomarie, or copyhold Tennant <note place="margin">36 <hi>The like he may doe for non payment of the quitrent.</hi>
                     </note> of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them, ſhall not pay his rents for his copyhold for which the ſame is due, and demanded by the ſaid Reeue, or his De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putie: Then it ſhall b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e lawfull for the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Mannor or Mannors for the time being or his or their Officers to diſtraine and anow, and for want of ſufficient diſtreſſe to ſeize the lands and tenements out of the which the ſame
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:135289:22"/> ought to be paid, and to take and enioy the rents iſſues and profits of the ſame to his or their owne vſe, vntill he or they ſhalbe fully ſatiſfied and paide the ſame rents by him or them that ſo ought to pay the ſame.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That when any Tenant dyeth ſeized lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing <note place="margin">37 <hi>Who ſhalbe Gardian.</hi>
                     </note> his heire vnder the age of fourteene yeeres the next of the kinne to whom the ſaid Lands and Tenements cannot diſcend ſhall haue if hee ſhall require it the cuſtodie of the heire, and of his lands and tenements committed vnto him for the vſe of the heire vntill he come to the age of fourteene yeeres as is aforeſaid, &amp; then he to chooſe his own <note place="margin">
                        <hi>See article.</hi> 33.</note> Gardian, and the former Gardian at any time af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter vpon reaſonable requeſt to yeeld accompt to the heyre of the profits of his lands receiued.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any perſon or perſons be diſpoſed to let his or their cuſtomarie Lands or Tenements to any other perſon or perſons, and to their execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors <note place="margin">38 <hi>Tennants may let leaſes for</hi> 31 <hi>yeeres and foure months without any ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence or Fine:</hi>
                     </note> and aſſignes for the terme of one and thirtie yeeres, or leſſe, the ſame perſon or perſons haue and ſhall haue full power and authoritie to ſet or let to farme his or their Copyhold Lands or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements to any perſon or perſons, their executors adminiſtrators and aſſignes, for the terme of one and thirtie yeeres, and foure monethes or leſſe, in <note place="margin">
                        <hi>See the abſtract of the inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture. pag.</hi> 7.</note> poſſeſſion from the time of the making thereof, by writing, without any licence to him or them to be granted, and without paying any fine to the Lord, or incurring any forfeiture, or ſeiſure of or for the ſame. So as the ſame leaſe doe not exceede one and thirtie yeeres and foure monethes from the
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:135289:23"/> time of the making thereof. But ſuch leaſe is and <note place="margin">If ſuch leaſes be not preſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>n<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to the ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage within on yeere after the making they ſhall be void.</note> ought to be preſented to the Homage of the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor whereof the Lands or tenements ſo leaſed are held within one yeere after the making thereof, or elſe the ſame leaſe ſo made, and not preſented as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid ſhalbe void, and of none effect.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The cuſtome of the Mannor is to giue to <note place="margin">39 <hi>Either mannor is vpon euery chaung of Lord to pay fiue pounds for re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cognition mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney.</hi>
                     </note> the Lord of euery of the ſaid Mannors, vpon the change of euery Lor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> at the next Court after the firſt entry <hi>bona fide</hi> ten pounds of lawfull money of England, <hi>That is to ſay,</hi> out of each Mannor fiue pounds for the Recognition and<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> acknowledging the ſeruices which is to be leauied and collected by the Reeue for the time being, amongſt all the Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyholders of the ſaid Mannors reſpectiuely ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the rates they ſhalbe taxed at by the Homage at the next Court to bee holden after the comming of the new Lord.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Homage of euery of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors <note place="margin">40 <hi>How the Reeue of either ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor is to be cho<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſen.</hi>
                     </note> ought yeerely at the generall Court to be hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den next after Michaelmas to elect and chooſe ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uerall Reeues for euery of the ſaid Mannors: That is to ſay to elect and chooſe two cuſtomarie Tenants either of the ſaid perſons named parties to the ſaid preſents their heires or aſſignes, or of others not named to beare the Office of the Reeue for each of the ſaid Mannors, namely he that was before in election if he be aliue and one other, or if he be dead two other, to the intent the Lord of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them or his Ste<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward may appoint, the one of them ſo elected for one whole yeere, that is one to ſerue for each of the
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:135289:23"/> ſaid Mannors. So hee be appointed within that Mannor of which he is a tenant, and for which he ſhalbe ſo choſen, which Reeue being ſo appointed <note place="margin">He ſhall ſerue one whole yere</note> ought to take vpon him the ſaid Office for one whole yeere then next enſuing, to execute the ſame by himſelfe or his Deputie for whom he ſhall an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwere, and to be ſubiect to accompt and anſwere <note place="margin">What ſine he ſhall pay if he refuſe.</note> for the ſame, as in the ſaid preſents is ſet downe: And if a Copy-holder ſhalbe duely choſen and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the Homage to bee the Lords Reeue as aforeſaid, and according to his turne preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by the Homage and ſhall refuſe to ſerue the ſaid Office by himſelfe or his Deputic, then euery ſuch perſon ſo refuſing within the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor of <hi>Hackney,</hi> ſhall pay for a fine ſixe pounds thirteene ſhillings and foure pence. And euery ſuch perſon, ſo re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>uſing within the ſaid Mannor of <note place="margin">The homage ſhall choſe ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther vntill one doe accept and ſerue-</note> 
                     <hi>Stebenhuth</hi> ſhall pay for a fine ten pounds to the Lord of the Mannor whereof his Lands are hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den. And the Homage of the ſame Mannor ſhal be charged from time to time, to chooſe another Reeue in the place of him that ſo ſhall refuſe, vntill ſuch time as for the ſame Mannor one bee choſen, that ſhall and w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ll ſerue the ſaid Office. And euery Copyholder that ſhalbe choſen and appointed to the ſaid Office as aforeſaid and ſhal refuſe to ſerue the ſame office ſhall pay the fine aforeſaid to the Lord of that Mannor for his refuſall the one halfe <note place="margin">The halfe of fines payd by re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſers ſhalbe al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed him, who next ſhall ſerue.</note> of all which fine or fines of Tenant or Tennants ſo refuſing to accept and execute the ſaid office of Reeueſhip, according to the true meaning of theſe Schedules, the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:135289:24"/> or either of them of whom reſpectiuely ſuch tenant or tenants ſo refuſing ſhall hold ought, and ſhall from time to time allow vnto ſuch perſon or perſons as being choſen and appointed to be Reeue as aforeſaid, and ſhall and will next after the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſall of any one or more of the ſaid tenants ſo cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen, accept and ſerue the ſaid office, the moyetie of the ſaid Fine or Fines reſpectiuely to be by him de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faulked and retained in his accompt, and by the Lord of that Mannor vpon the ſame Reeues ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compt <note place="margin">And be by him retayned at his accompting.</note> whenſoeuer he ſhall accompt for the ſame to be allowed.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any Copyholder that ſhall accept and <note place="margin">41 <hi>In what caſes the Lord may ſeeſe the Reeues lands.</hi>
                     </note> execute the ſaid office of Reeue ſhall refuſe to ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſfie and pay vnto the Lord the yeerely quitrents and Fines for admittances vpon alienations or diſcents wherewith ſuch Reeue ſhall or may be law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully charged by and according to the true meaning of theſe preſents; Or ſhall refuſe to accompt with the Lord within two moneths next yeerely after <hi>Michaelmas</hi> hauing had the Rentall and eſtracts of Fines vpon admittances as aforeſaid for that yeere by the ſpace of two moneths. Euery ſuch Reeues lands and tenements that ſhal refuſe ſo to accompt, and pay the ſaid rents and fines which he ſhall or may haue collected as aforeſaid, ſhalbe ſei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed into the Lords hands, and the Lord ſhall and may take to his owne vſe the iſſues and profits of his ſaid lands and tenements, vntill he ſhall pay vnto the Lord, the rents and fines aforeſaid, and vntill he hath alſo ſatiſfied, and paid the Lord for <note place="margin">And what he ſhall pay for his offence.</note> his ſaid offence <hi>(viz.)</hi> being Reeue of <hi>Hackney,</hi> ſixe
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:135289:24"/> pounds thirteene ſhillings and foure pence. And being Reeue of <hi>Stebunhuth</hi> ten pounds. Neuerthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſe the Reeue ought not, nor ſhall be charged, or chargeable to anſwere any quitrents contained in any rentall or eſtracts, vnleſſe it appeare vnto him <note place="margin">He is not to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwere any quit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rents, vnles he know the ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant or where the land lyeth.</note> by the rentall of the former Reeue, or otherwiſe be made knowne vnto him by ſome of the Lords officers who is the tenant, or where the land ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth, for or in reſpect of which the ſame quitrents ought to be paid.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> No copyholder of the ſaid Mannors or of <note place="margin">42 <hi>No Reeues within this co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                           <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition, ſhallbe charged with the Leet, or court baron o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe then in the</hi> 41. <hi>article.</hi>
                     </note> either of them, being named parties to the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture nor their heires or aſſignes ought or ſhall at any tune bee charged to collect or gather any of the amerciaments, fines, or other iſſues or profits of the Courts Leetes, or Courts Baron holden within the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, or be chargeable to anſwere or accompt for the ſame, to the Lord of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, otherwiſe then in the laſt precedent Article is mentioned, nor to prouide or allow for any din<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, <note place="margin">Nor prouide for any dinner<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</note> either on the day or daies the Court Leete ſhalbe holden vpon, or on the day or dayes of the two generall Courts. But are and ſhalbe thereof for euer freed and diſcharged. Except that ſuch te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant <note place="margin">Except &amp;c.</note> or his heires ſhall hereafter purchaſe or haue other cuſtomary lands then thoſe that the ſaid per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons named parties to the ſaid Indenture, or ſome or one of them the ſaid perſons doe now hold, which ſhalbe worth to bee ſold at the leaſt two hundred pounds of lawfull money of England, or ſhalbe of the cleere yerely value of twenty pounds of like money.</p>
                  <pb n="44" facs="tcp:135289:25"/>
                  <p> 
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Euery one of the ſaid cuſtomarie tennants <note place="margin">43 <hi>What tennants may be choſen Recues.</hi>
                     </note> named parties to the ſaid Indenture whoſe lands Tenements and Hereditaments holden by Copie of Court Roll of either of the ſaid Mannors, are worth ſixeteene pounds of like mony as aforeſaid by the yeere to be let, or two hundred pounds to be ſold, by the eſtimation and preſentment of the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage of the ſame Mannor ſhall beare the office of Reeue of and for ſuch of the ſaid Mannors where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of he ſhalbe a Tenant by copie of Court Roll, and for which hee ſhalbe choſen and appointed Reeue as aforeſaid, when his or their time and courſe doth come.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Euery of the ſaid Reeues, is to be allowed <note place="margin">44 <hi>What allowan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces the Reeue is to haue of the Lord.</hi>
                     </note> of the ſaid Lord or Lords for the executing of the ſaid office for one yeere as followeth: <hi>(viz.)</hi> the Reeue of <hi>Stebunhuth</hi> three pounds ſixe ſhillings and eight pence, and ſix ſhillings eight pence more for and in reſpect of an allowance of a coate cloth to the ſaid Reeue. And the Reeue of <hi>Hackney</hi> fiftie three ſhillings and foure pence, and ſixe ſhillings eight pence more, for and in reſpect of an allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of a coate cloth to the ſame Reeue, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther commodities due and incident to the ſaid of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, for either of them, or vſed heretofore to be paid to the ſaid Reeue, by any the Tenants of the ſaid Mannors reſpectiuely.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Reeues of the ſaid Mannors, and of either of them ſhall at the next generall Court, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter <note place="margin">45 <hi>The Reeue to deliuer the Ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tall to his Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſor. To be amerced</hi>
                     </note> his yeere of ſeruice expired deliuer the rentall by which hee made his accompt to the Reeue that ſhall next ſucceede him vpon paine to bee amer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:135289:25"/> or fined by the Homage if hee ſhall not ſo doe.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> All the cuſtomarie Tenants of the ſaid <note place="margin">46 <hi>Copyholders may breake and digge their grounds, fell downe timber &amp; woods: ſuffer howſen <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap> decay: without forfeicture.</hi>
                     </note> Mannors and of either of them may breake and digge their copyhold grounds holden of the ſaid Mannors and of either of them at his and their pleaſure, and fell and cut downe their timber and woods growing, or that ſhall grow vpon the ſame, and conuert it to their beſt vſe and profit, and may alſo ſuffer their Copyhold Tenements and houſes to decay without incurring any ſeizure or forfeiture of their eſtates therefore, or other paine, and may take and pull downe their ſaid Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and erect or ſet them vp againe, either where they ſtood before, or vpon any other lands holden by copy of Court Roll of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, <note place="margin">But may not pull downe howſen to ſet them vpon free hold land</note> or of either of them. But they may not, or ſhall not take or pull them downe to ſet them or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny part of them vpon their owne Free-holds, or vpon the Freeholds of any other. <note place="margin">47 <hi>Copyholders may lopp trees growing vpon the waſt before their howſen.</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Euery of the ſaid copyholders, or reputed copyholders named parties to the ſaid Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures may lop and ſhred all ſuch trees as grow be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore their houſes or Tenements vpon the waſte ground, and the ſame conuert to their owne vſe <note place="margin">May dig grauell &amp;c. vpon the waſt.</note> without any offence ſo the ſaid trees ſtand for the defence of their houſes, yards, or gardens, and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo may digge grauell, ſand, clay and lome vpon the ſaid waſte grounds to build or repaire any of their copyhold Tenements within the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, or in either of them without any licence. So alwaies as euery of the ſaid copyholders doe fill vp ſo much as ſhalbe digged by him or them.</p>
                  <pb n="46" facs="tcp:135289:26"/>
                  <p> 
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any perſon or perſons being Tenant <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Letting of lands for more then</hi> 31 <hi>yeeres</hi> 4 <hi>months is a for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feicture.</hi>
                     </note> cuſtomarie ſhall without licence by Indenture or other writing or otherwiſe let his ſaid cuſtomarie Lands or Tenements for more yeeres then one and thirtie yeeres and foure moneths, it ſhalbe a forfeiture of his eſtate by the cuſtome of the ſaid Mannors, and of either of them being found and preſented by the Homage, or elſe otherwiſe lawful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and ſufficiently proued.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> For Treaſon or Felony whatſoeuer that ſhalbe committed by any Copy-holder of the ſaid <note place="margin">49 <hi>For what offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces theſe copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders ſhall forfeit their eſtates.</hi>
                     </note> Mannors or of any of them for which hee ſhalbe lawfully attainted, hee ſhall forfeit his Copyhold Lands and Tenements to the Lord of the ſaid Mannor. And for all other offence, or offences, act or acts whatſoeuer, for which a Free-holder ought by the common lawes of the land to forfeit his free-hold lands and tenements, there a Copy-hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them ſhall forfeit as a Free-holder ought to forfeit in like caſe his Free hold. But if a copyholder be out-lawed for any cauſe ſauing Treaſon or Felony, the Lord <note place="margin">Outlaw<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ie, vn<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>les for treaſon or felony, ſhalbe no forfeiture</note> ſhall not haue the iſſues or profits of his lands. And if a copyholder make a Feoffement of his co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold, gift in taile, or leaſe for life or liues by Deede or without Deede, by liuerie and ſeizin therevpon, or ſhall ſuffer a Recouerie at the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon <note place="margin">More forfeitur of eſtate. viz. making a Feof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fements guift in tale, leaſe for liues, ſuffering a Recoldy at the common law.</note> law<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> leuie a Fine, or wilfully refuſe, and deny to pay, doe, or performe his rents, fines, ſuites cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes and ſeruices at any time hereafter due to the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Mannors, or of ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of them, for their ſaid copyholds, the ſame wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:135289:26"/> refuſall being preſented to the Homage by the <note place="margin">Leuijng a fine or willfull deny<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing to pay the rents, fines &amp;c.</note> oathes of three cuſtomarie Tennants with the Reeue or his Deputie, (the ſaid Tennants or Reeue, nor his Deputy being none of the Lords ſeruants) and being found and preſented by the ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage, the ſame ſhalbe holden and reputed a for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture of his eſtate, whatſoeuer hee ſhall haue by copy of Court Roll, at the time of any ſuch act, committed or done in ſo much of his and their co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold Lands and Tenements as hee ſhall haue committed any ſuch act &amp; onely for ſo much of his lands &amp; tenements out of the which the ſaid quit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent and other duties is demanded, and ſhalbe due, and wilfully denied by the ſaid Tenant or tenants as aforeſaid. Or if any copyholder ſhall in the <note place="margin">Or diſclaiming to hold of the Lord.</note> Lords Court or elſewhere in any Court of Record diſclaime to hold his ſaid copyhold Lands and te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements of the Lord of the Mannor whereof his Lands and tenements are holden, or ſhall by plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding in the Lords Court, or other Court of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord <note place="margin">Or claiming their copy-holds to be free holds.</note> wilfully claime their copyholds to bee Free-holds, or willingly and wittingly pleade in any Real action at the common law in chiefe as a Free-hold <note place="margin">Or plead wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tingly in a reall action at com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon law in chiefe as a Free-holder.</note> Tenant or ſhall willingly and wittingly doe any other act, or things in or concerning his now Lands and tenements which ſhalbe a diſſeiſin or diſinheritance of the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, their heires or aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignes <note place="margin">Or doe any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther act which ſhalbe a diſſei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſin of the Lord.</note> (other then ſuch acts as in theſe Articles are eſpeciall mentioned or diſpenſed withall) that then hee ſhall forfeit his and their eſtate of and in the ſame Lands and Tenements ſo diſclaimed to
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:135289:27"/> be holden or claimed to be Freehold, or for which he ſhall pleade in chiefe or doe any ſuch other act or thing as is aforeſaid. Finally, the Lord of the ſaid <note place="margin">What other forfeictures the Lord ſhall haue.</note> Mannors, or of either of them ſhall haue all ſuch other forfeitures, iſſues, profits, and aduantages of the ſaid Copyholds as ſha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>l grow due to him by any Statute, Lawes of this Realme being not againſt and contrarie to theſe Articles &amp; cuſtomes heere expreſſely ſet downe.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any perſon or perſons hauing any eſtate <note place="margin">50 <hi>The act or neglect of ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant for liues or yeeres ſhall not preiudice thoſe in remainder.</hi>
                     </note> of any copyhold lands or tenements holden of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them for terme of life, or liues, or for terme of yeeres, or in the right of their wiues of any eſtate although he, ſhe, or they, ſhall doe or ſuffer, or neglect to doe any act or acts, during the time aforeſaid, in or vpon the ſaid Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold Lands, or Tenements, which may or ſhal be contrary to the cuſtome of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them. The ſame act or acts, ſo being done ſhall not preiudice or be hurtfull vnto the next perſon or perſons to whom the ſaid cuſtomarie Lands or tenements ſhould or ought to remaine, reuert or come, nor to the ſaid wife or her heires, not being partie in Court, or conſenting in Court to the ſaid act or forfeiture, nor that the Lord of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them ſhall take any longer aduantage, iſſues, or profits of the ſame Copyhold Lands or Tenements then during the time of ſuch eſtates as is aforeſaid, of the partie committing, doing, or aſſenting, to ſuch act or acts. So that after his or their deceaſe or eſtates determined the ſaid Lands and Tenements ſhall
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:135289:27"/> remaine, reuert, or come to the next perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, or to ſuch perſon or perſons, to whom the ſame ſhould haue comen or remained, or goe, or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uert immediately after ſuch eſtate or eſtates ended or determined, as though there had beene no ſuch act or acts done, contrary to the tenor or true mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, of theſe preſents by any ſuch perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The particular or priuate act or acts of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny <note place="margin">51 <hi>The priuat act of any tennants contrary to theſe articles, ſhall not extend to be a breach of the cuſtomes to the hurt of the reſt.</hi>
                     </note> cuſtomary Tennant or tenants of any of the ſaid Mannors which ſhall happen to be done<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully by or betweene them, or any of them, and the Lord or Lords of the ſaid Mannors or either of them, and his or their Reeue, or of either of them, contrarie to the Articles, &amp; true meaning of theſe preſents neither doth nor ſhal extend to be co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſtrued to bee a breach of the ancient Cuſtomes of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them, to the hurt or pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iudice of the reſt of the cuſtomarie Tenants but of themſelues onely doing the ſaid particular act. <note place="margin">52 <hi>Tennant for life or yeeres, making waſt, ſhalbe fined by the homage.</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That if any Tennant for terme of life, or liues onely, or for terme of yeeres of cuſtomarie Lands ſhall make any waſte, Then hee ſhalbe fi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ned by the Homage, the third part of which fine, ſhalbe to the Lord, and the other two parts ſhall come to him in the Reuertion or Remainder of the ſaid copyhold.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Lord for none payment of amercia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments <note place="margin">53 <hi>For non pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of amer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciame<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ts the Lord may diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>traine, but not ſeiſe.</hi>
                     </note> may diſtraine his ſaid Tennants parties to theſe preſents, and auow for the ſame as for Rents. But hee cannot ſeize any of his or their Lands or Tenements parties to theſe preſents
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:135289:28"/> for <hi>non</hi> payment thereof vntill he be paid.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Vpon the admiſſion of any co-heires, ioint Tennants, or Tennants in common if they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not <note place="margin">54 <hi>How partition is to be made betweene co-heires ioynt tennants or ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon.</hi>
                     </note> agree to occupie their Lands and Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments together, or to make partition among them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelues, then hee or they that bee grieued may by the cuſtome of either of the ſaid Mannors haue a precept from the Steward directed to ſeuen cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marie Tennants, or more of the ſaid Mannors within which the ſaid Lands and tenements doe lye; and they ſhall make partition thereof, and the ſame returne to the Steward of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors againe to be inrolled in the Court Rolls of the ſaid Mannors, whereof the ſaid Lands or Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments beholden. Whervpon the ſaid heires ſhal go to the Steward of the ſaid Mannor within which the ſaid lands or tenements ſhall lye. And then e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect &amp; chooſe their parts in forme following (<hi>That is to ſay,</hi> the yongeſt ſonne to chooſe firſt, then he that is next to the yongeſt to chuſe next, and ſo after that rate vnto the eldeſt (how many ſoeuer,) which eldeſt ſhal chuſe laſt. And likewiſe the ſame order is to be obſerued amongſt daughters if there be no ſonnes. and amongſt all other degrees of heires touching the cuſtomarie Lands and Tenements holden of the ſaid Mannors or either of them. And vpon euery ſuch partition, they ſhall pay for a fine to the Lord two ſhillings and ſixe pence or leſſe at the diſcretion, of the Steward, according to the quantitie of the Lands or Tenements ſo parted betweene tennants in common, and ioynt tenants for the like fine the ſaid deuiſion to bee by the ſaid
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:135289:28"/> Tenants without election of the parties them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelues but by caſting of lots, if they cannot other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe agree.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any cuſtomarie or free Tenants cattell, <note place="margin">55 <hi>Theſe copyhol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders ſhall pay but one penny for poundage.</hi>
                     </note> or the cattell of their Farmers, bee brought to the Lords pound. The ſaid Tenant or his Farmer ſhall pay for all his cattell if they bee a hundred heads or vpwards or vnder for the poundage thereof but one penny, and he that is no Tenant ſhall pay for euery diſtreſſe of cattell ſo pounded foure pence. <note place="margin">56 <hi>Cattell im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded to be deliuered by two copyholders.</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If any cattell bee impounded within the Lords pound, by any perſon or perſons being a cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomarie Tenant or Tennants of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors or of either of them for any treſpaſſe com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted or done, within the ſaid Mannors or in ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of them vpon their Copyholds, that all ſuch Cattell being ſo impounded may by two of the ſaid cuſtomarie Tenants of ſuch of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them wherein the ſaid treſpaſſe ſhall bee committed which will anſwere for ſuch Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mages and coſts as ſhalbe recouered in the ſaid Court againſt the owners of the ſame Cattell for the ſaid treſpaſſe be deliuered out of the ſaid pound vnto the owner of the ſaid Cattell, by the cuſtome of the ſame Mannors and of either of them.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> No cuſtomarie Tenant ſhall ſue, vexe, or <note place="margin">57 <hi>No ſu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>tes for ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of copy-holds out of the Lords court withou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence.</hi>
                     </note> trouble any other cuſtomary Tenant for any Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of lands or tenements lying and being within the ſaid Mannors, or in either of them being copy-hold lands or tenements of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, out of the Lords Court, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:135289:29"/> the ſpeciall licence firſt had and obtained of the Lord of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them, or of his Steward for the time being. If any perſon doe the contrarie, hee ſhall haue his Lands or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements ſeized into the Lords hands, vntill hee pay a fine to the Lord for the ſame offence, <hi>(viz.)</hi> ſuch fine as ſhalbe ceaſſed by the Homage at the next generall Court of the ſaid Mannor or Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That no cuſtomarie Tenants of the ſaid <note place="margin">58 <hi>Cattell offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding ſhalbe dri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ue<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to the Lords pound.</hi>
                     </note> Mannors or of either of them, for any offence to be done by any mans cattel within the ſaid Mannors or in either of them, ſhall driue the ſame cattell to any forraine pounds, but to the Lords pound be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing within the ſaid Mannors or in either of them, if any man doe the contrarie to bee amerced at the next generall Court by the Homage. So alwayes as there be aſufficient pound of the Lords there.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> That no tenant or any other perſon ſhall <note place="margin">59 <hi>How ſtakes markes and mears between tennant &amp; ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant ought to be ſet.</hi>
                     </note> ſet any ſtake, marke, or meare, betweene tennant, and tennant, or betweene tenant, and any other perſon that lyeth next vnto him, without the par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties doe therevnto agree, vnleſſe an order bee ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the Homage, or the greateſt part of them that it may be firſt viewed, by twelue Tennants of the ſaid Mannors, or of either of them where the ſtake, or meare is to be ſet, and there to ſet the ſtake or marke indifferently betweene both the ſaid parties, and ſo to continue it vpon paine of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merciament by the Homage. <note place="margin">60 <hi>Driuers of com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>mons when to be choſen,</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Homage doe and ſhall yeerely vſe at the next generall Court holden the Tueſday the
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:135289:29"/> ninth day next after Eaſter day to Elect, and chuſe out of the Hamblets within euery of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors certaine cuſtomary tennants to bee driuers and viewers of the waſts and commons of the ſaid Mannors and of either of them for one whole yeere, which tenants ſo elected haue authoritie by the ſaid cuſtome to driue the commons at any time when they finde it ſurcharged, and to impound the cattell by them ſo taken, &amp; no other to driue the ſaid common then the perſons ſo choſen as aforeſaid.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If by their driuing the ſurcharging can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be remedied, then they ought to inform the ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage <note place="margin">61 <hi>How ſurchar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon is to be, remedied.</hi>
                     </note> thereof at the next Court, that they may a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce the offenders, whether the offenders be te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants or no tenants And alſo to put a paine or an a merciament vpon their heads, that they ſhall not likewiſe offend.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> If the ſaid driuers receiue by the ſaid poun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dages <note place="margin">62 <hi>The driuers ſhall accompt to the homage.</hi>
                     </note> and more money then they ſpend in their trauell, the reſt ſhalbe imployed to the ſcowring of the common Sewers, which be vpon the ſaid waſt grounds and commons, and laying of bridges ouer the ſaid common Sewers, and ſhall make their accompt in that behalfe to the Homage at the generall Court, when the yeere for which they were choſen ſhall expire. <note place="margin">63 <hi>The homage may make By<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawes which ſhall binde the tennants.</hi>
                     </note>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The copyhold and cuſtomarie Tennants may make by lawes at their generall Courts when neede ſhall require, which cuſtome ſhalbe ſo continued, and the ſaid by lawes ſo by them made ſhall binde all the Copyhold Tenants of the ſaid Mannors or of either of them, ſo the ſame bee not
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:135289:30"/> contrarie to the true meaning of theſe Articles.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> By the cuſtome of the ſaid Mannors, and of either of them Tennants in taile of cuſtomarie <note place="margin">64 <hi>Recoueryes may be ſuffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to barre in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tailes.</hi>
                     </note> lands and tenements may ſuffer common recoue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries within the ſaid ſeuerall Mannors with ſingle or double vouchers or by agreement forfeit the ſaid lands and tenements into the Lords hands for the cutting of the eſtate taile, which cuſtome by theſe Articles ſhal haue ſtill continuance, and ſuch Recoueries and forfeitures, are and ſhall bee good to bare the ſaid in-taile.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> Whenſoeuer there ſhalbe any Court or <note place="margin">65 <hi>Tennants not appearing at ſet courtes ſhall not be amerced aboue</hi> 4 <hi>pence,</hi>
                     </note> Courts Baron (or other then the ſaid two generall Courts) kept within the ſaid Mannors or either of them no copyholder ought nor ſhall be amerced a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boue the ſumme of foure pence for any default of his apparance at any the ſame Court or Courts (except the ſaid two generall Courts) neither ſhall incurre any forfeiture, or ſeiſure of his Copyhold lands or tenements, or any other Damage for any ſuch default. And the ſaid Amerciament to bee taxed by the Affurors tenants of that Court.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Steward or his Deputy is to haue <note place="margin">66 <hi>The Stewards fees.</hi>
                     </note> ſuch Fees and allowances as hereafter are expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, <hi>(viz.)</hi> for euery Surrender taken out of Court fiue ſhillings, and nothing for any Surrender ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken in Court, (for euery woman couert Baron) that ſhalbe examined, ſixe ſhillings eight pence, for euery admittance of euery perſon two ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, for entering euery Surrender and making the copie of Court Roll therevpon ſixe ſhillings eight pence, for euery precept for a view of parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:135289:30"/> and entring the ſame, and the returne thereof vpon the Court Roll, and the copie thereof two ſhillings ſixe pence. And if it exceede two ſheetes of paper then for euery ſheete ouer and aboue two ſheetes twelue pence more. For ſearching the court Rolls for euery yeere foure pence. For euery pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſed Court thirteene ſhillings foure pence: For entring a note of a Leaſe granted of any Lands or tenements containing the date, quantitie of lands or tenements, &amp; certaintie of terme &amp; to whom the ſame ſhalbe granted, and for a note thereof to the party ſixe pence. For theſe things before expreſſed the Steward ſhall haue onely ſuch Fees as before is declared, and for all other things hee ſhall haue as formerly hath anciently beene vſed &amp; not more.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> All Meſſuages, Tenements, and Cotta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges <note place="margin">67 <hi>Buildings to be erected, ſhall pay fines as thoſe allreadie built.</hi>
                     </note> that ſhall hereafter bee built vpon any the co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhol Lands, whereof the cuſtomes are hereby meant to bee declared, ſhalbe held and enioyed by the copyhold Tenants thereof vnder the ſame cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes and Articles herein declared as the Lands whereon they ſhal be built are holden and enioyed. (But ſhall pay ſuch fines) therefore as is before declared for Meſſuages, Tenements and Cotta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges <note place="margin">68 <hi>The Lord ſhall not ſeuer from the mannor any of theſe copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holds, to any perſons in fee ſimple, or other eſtate of free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold &amp;c.</hi>
                     </note> that ſhalbe new built.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Item,</hi> The Lord of the ſaid Mannors, or of ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of them, their heires or aſſignes ſhal not at any time hereafter grant or conuey ſeuered, from the Mannor wherof the ſame is now holden, or ought to bee holden any of the Meſſuages, Cottages, Lands, Tenemements or Hereditaments where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of any of the ſaid perſons named parties to the ſaid
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:135289:31"/> Indenture herevnto annexed is now copyholder or cuſtomarie Tenant to any perſon or perſons in Fee-ſimple, Fee-taile, or for terme of life, or other eſtate of freehold, or for any eſtate, or terme other then by copie of Court Roll, according to the cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes of the ſaid Mannors, and true meaning of theſe preſents, and the Iudenture whereunto the ſame are annexed, except the Freehold to be gran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted or ſeuered at the petition and deſire of ſuch perſon or perſons as then ſhalbe copyholder there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, according to the true meaning of theſe preſents. And it the Lord hath granted away the Freehold of any the copyhold Lands or Tenements wher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the cuſtome is hereby ment to be declared, hee ſhall get, and take the ſame backe againe, and the ſame ſhall notwithſtanding ſuch grant or alienati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on be annexed to the Mannor whereof it was, or is held, and ſhalbe held and enioyed by the Tenant his heires and aſſignes thereof, by copie of Court Roll of the ſame Mannor vnder the rents, ſerui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces and cuſtomes in theſe Articles expreſſed, and not otherwiſe. And alſo that the Lord ſhall admit by his Steward or his Deputy, all ſuch Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant and Tenants that ought of right to be admitted vpon the preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Homage.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="list_of_tenants">
                  <pb n="57" facs="tcp:135289:31"/>
                  <head>AN ALPHABETICALL TABLE OF THE <hi>NAMES OF THE COPYHOLD TENANTS</hi> OF THE MANNORS OF STEPNEY <hi>alias</hi> STEBVNHVTH, and HACKNEY for whom the ſaid Decree concerning the cuſtomes aforeſa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d was made in <hi>Chancerie</hi> the two and twentieth day of <hi>Iuly</hi> in the <hi>fifteenth yeere of the raigne of our Soueraigne</hi> Lord King <hi>Iames</hi> againſt the ſaid Right Honorable <hi>Thomas Lord Wentworth</hi> then Lord of the ſaid Mannors.</head>
                  <list>
                     <head>A</head>
                     <item>VIncent Amcots <hi>Limehouſe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iacob Aſhley <hi>Limehouſe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Adams <hi>Limehouſe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Will. Ardington <hi>White Chappel.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Abbot <hi>Popler.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iane Alder <hi>Popler.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Nicholas Ask with <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Alder <hi>of Ratcliffe highway.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>B</head>
                     <item>William Bygot <hi>Ratcliffe</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Barnet <hi>White Chappell.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Robert Borne <hi>Pop.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Hugh Bullock &amp; <hi>vxor.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henr. Baniſter Eſquire <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Bird &amp; <hi>vx. Hackney:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Nicholas Burton <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Edward Browne <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Gyles Bynckes <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Gyles de Budt <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Edmond Barbor
<list>
                           <item>Oldford.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henry Barbor</item>
                     <item>Francis Barbor.</item>
                     <item>Tho: Baxter &amp; vxor, <hi>Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Michael Bonner, <hi>Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Briggs &amp; vxor, <hi>Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Chriſtopher Baker
<list>
                           <item>Ratcliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Browne</item>
                     <item>Robert Benns</item>
                     <item>Peter Baker</item>
                     <item>Alice Bland</item>
                     <item>Raph Bowers</item>
                     <item>Thomas Beſt.</item>
                     <item>Queſcell Bratoſt, alias Lee
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Ball</item>
                     <item>Iohn Bennet</item>
                     <item>Robert Bradſhaw</item>
                     <item>Mathew Barret</item>
                     <pb n="58" facs="tcp:135289:32"/>
                     <item> Richard Bromfield</item>
                     <item>Elizabeth Bedford</item>
                     <item>Iohn Bigot.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>C</head>
                     <item>Thomas Commins.</item>
                     <item>Nicholas Coſens</item>
                     <item>Thomas Crane.</item>
                     <item>Richard Catcher.</item>
                     <item>Edward Catcher.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Croxall.</item>
                     <item>William Cooke &amp; vxor, Walter Henley <hi>in Reuerſion.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Catcher
<list>
                           <item>Hackney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Catcher</item>
                     <item>Richard Cheyney</item>
                     <item>Francis Clerkevid.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Catcher</item>
                     <item>William Catcher</item>
                     <item>Thomas Catcher.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Cowper
<list>
                           <item>White Chappell.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Tho: Coxan.</item>
                     <item>Walter Cooke
<list>
                           <item>Ratcliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Walter Coale.</item>
                     <item>Peter Croxall.</item>
                     <item>Mary Cope
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Elizabeth Clerke.</item>
                     <item>Marion Criſpe
<list>
                           <item>Popler.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Mary Carpenter.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Chandler
<list>
                           <item>Bowe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Clarke</item>
                     <item>George Cooke, <hi>Inholder</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iſaack Cotton.</item>
                     <item>Richard Catcher, fil. Tho:</item>
                     <item>Iohn Coleman; <hi>White Chappell.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>D</head>
                     <item>Nicholas Diggins, <hi>Mileend.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Dickinſon
<list>
                           <item>Hackney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iames Deane</item>
                     <item>William Dauis.</item>
                     <item>Nicholas Dickens, <hi>Stepney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Hugh Dauis, <hi>White Chappell.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Alexander Dauiſon
<list>
                           <item>Popler.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iames Dauies</item>
                     <item>George Dethicke</item>
                     <item>Gilbert Dethick</item>
                     <item>Henry Dethicke.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Day, <hi>Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Rachel Dauiſon.</item>
                     <item>Robert Dixon, <hi>White Chappell.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>E</head>
                     <item>Iohn Eaglefield, <hi>and</hi> Iane <hi>his wife.</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>Bow</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Richard Edwards</item>
                     <item>Alexander Elcock.</item>
                     <item>Richard Elcock.</item>
                     <item>George Edwards, <hi>Shorditch.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Ewens.
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Euans.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Engliſh.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>F</head>
                     <item>Raph Flauell, <hi>Ratcliffe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Flint, <hi>Limehouſe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Forſter, <hi>Bow.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Fell, <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>Fuller widdow, <hi>Ratcliffe.</hi>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <pb n="59" facs="tcp:135289:32"/>
                     <head>G</head>
                     <item>William Gough, <hi>Bow</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Goddard</item>
                     <item>Vincent Goddard.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Garland
<list>
                           <item>Bow.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Richard Gouge.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Graues
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Michael Geere.</item>
                     <item>Iohn George.</item>
                     <item>Roger Gunſton
<list>
                           <item>Ratcliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Roger Glouer</item>
                     <item>Iohn Gunſton.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Goddard.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Gruit &amp; vxor.</item>
                     <item>Richard
<list>
                           <item>Glouer.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn</item>
                     <item>Francis</item>
                     <item>Robert</item>
                     <item>Thomas</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>H</head>
                     <item>Sir Ferdinando Heyborne
<list>
                           <item>Hackney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Greſham Hogan</item>
                     <item>Henry Haynes</item>
                     <item>Thomas Hawkes</item>
                     <item>Richard Harriſon.</item>
                     <item>Sr Tho: Hardreſſe <hi>Mileend</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>Mileend.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Robert Hart</item>
                     <item>Thomas Hogge</item>
                     <item>Will: Herendin</item>
                     <item>Robert Hunt.</item>
                     <item>Richard Hoskins
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Walter Hendley.</item>
                     <item>Richard Hale
<list>
                           <item>Ratcliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Robert Henricke.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Howland
<list>
                           <item>White</item>
                           <item>Chappel.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Cord well Hamond</item>
                     <item>Geor. Houghto<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> &amp; vx.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Halbrooke</item>
                     <item>Nicholas Hallam</item>
                     <item>Thomas Hartis</item>
                     <item>Waiter Hallyley</item>
                     <item>Elizabeth
<list>
                           <item>Hide.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Dorothy</item>
                     <item>Iohn Hils.
<list>
                           <item>Popler.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Harbert</item>
                     <item>Rob. Hickes</item>
                     <item>Will: Hanford.</item>
                     <item>Robert Hudſon.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Hether, <hi>Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Francis Hollyday.</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>The heyres of</hi> Haggis.</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>The heires of</hi> Tho: Hardcaſtle.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>I</head>
                     <item>Sir Iohn Iowles <hi>Knight Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Iuie
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Roger Iones</item>
                     <item>Margaret Iorden.</item>
                     <item>Michael Iones, <hi>et vxor Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Iones
<list>
                           <item>Ratliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Ienks</item>
                     <item>Ionas Iames.</item>
                     <pb n="60" facs="tcp:135289:33"/>
                     <item> Nicholas Iſack.</item>
                     <item>Adam Iohnſon <hi>Shoraitch.</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>Iones <hi>widdow, Limehouſe.</hi>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>K</head>
                     <item>Iohn Key <hi>Miles, Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Killingworth, <hi>Shorditch.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Knowles, <hi>Popler.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Kattle.</item>
                     <item>Iohn King, <hi>Limehouſe.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>L</head>
                     <item>Robert Linage.</item>
                     <item>Robert Lambard
<list>
                           <item>Bowe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Lowden.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Lawrence
<list>
                           <item>Ratliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>George Linum.</item>
                     <item>Richard Leigh, <hi>et vxor.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Dame</hi> Margaret Lake.</item>
                     <item>Richard Lowfield.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Lowfield.</item>
                     <item>William Lowfield.</item>
                     <item>Humfry Lowfield.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Linkes.</item>
                     <item>William Lyones
<list>
                           <item>Mil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>nd.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Lyones.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>M</head>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Sir</hi> Wil: Martin <hi>Knight</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>Hack:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Elizabeth Mackeris.</item>
                     <item>William Mansbridge.</item>
                     <item>Richard Mills,</item>
                     <item>Iohn Maynard
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Mynſhawe</item>
                     <item>Iſabell Moore</item>
                     <item>Iohn Moore</item>
                     <item>Michaell Merrial.</item>
                     <item>William Millar
<list>
                           <item>Shorditch.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>George Michell.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Mould
<list>
                           <item>Stepney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Edward Mathewes.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Maning, <hi>Ratliffe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henry maybancke
<list>
                           <item>whitechap:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Samuell Marſh</item>
                     <item>Thomas Marſh.</item>
                     <item>Eme Melſham <hi>vid.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Michell.</item>
                     <item>Anne Michell
<list>
                           <item>Popler.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Manſhippe.</item>
                     <item>Francis Moore, <hi>Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Richard Merrit.</item>
                     <item>Tho: Marſh <hi>Eſquire</hi>
                        <list>
                           <item>Milend.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Milton.</item>
                     <item>Ioane Manly.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>N</head>
                     <item>Iohn Newet
<list>
                           <item>Hackney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Newman</item>
                     <item>Iohn Nichols</item>
                     <item>Barbara Nichols.</item>
                     <item>Edward Nichols, <hi>Ratliffe</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Laurence Netmaker, <hi>Shorditch.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas newport, <hi>Limehouſe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Nichols <hi>Shipwrite.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>P</head>
                     <item>William Phillips <hi>ſen: Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Philips iun.
<list>
                           <item>Lime:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Richard Parkes</item>
                     <item>William Pond</item>
                     <item>William Peacocke</item>
                     <item>William Pointell</item>
                     <item>Giles Patricke, <hi>et vx.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <pb n="61" facs="tcp:135289:33"/>
                     <item> William Palmer, <hi>Bed. Greene.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Peirepoint, <hi>Whitechap:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Peirciuall, <hi>Bowe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henry Parſons, <hi>et vx. Shorditch.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henry Parſons
<list>
                           <item>Hackney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Miles Preſſick</item>
                     <item>Vincent Parrit, <hi>Popler.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Pettit.</item>
                     <item>Thomas pinnock.</item>
                     <item>Richard Pointell.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Pye.</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chriſtopher</hi> Potkin, <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Q</head>
                     <item>Mathew de Queſter.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>R</head>
                     <item>Samuell Rowley
<list>
                           <item>Whitechap.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Roger Robinſon</item>
                     <item>Anne Riland <hi>late</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>wife of Wil: Haggis.</item>
                     <item>Richard Rooding, <hi>Bowe</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Roberts.</item>
                     <item>Henry Reynolds, <hi>Popley.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Edward Ruſſell
<list>
                           <item>Ratliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Robert Rickman</item>
                     <item>Edmund Rolfe</item>
                     <item>Iohn Rolfe.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Railton,
<list>
                           <item>Popley.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Catherin Ruſhbrooke</item>
                     <item>Henry Riuers.</item>
                     <item>Richard Rowe, <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Rowe.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Rich
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Edith Read.</item>
                     <item>William Reeue</item>
                     <item>Elizabeth Rider</item>
                     <item>Bridget Rider</item>
                     <item>Katherin Rider</item>
                     <item>Griſſingon Rider.</item>
                     <item>Roger Roſe, <hi>White Chapple.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Roger Roſe and
<list>
                           <item>Hackney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Roſe.</item>
                     <item>William Swaine
<list>
                           <item>Hackney.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Steward</item>
                     <item>Iohn Shelley</item>
                     <item>Iohn Snape</item>
                     <item>Barthol. Smith.</item>
                     <item>George Saris, <hi>of London, Lime<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſe and Ratliffe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>William Simons, <hi>Limehouſe:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Peter Sumner
<list>
                           <item>Bowe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Salter, <hi>et vx:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Scorier</item>
                     <item>Edward Smith</item>
                     <item>Iames Short, <hi>Shorditch:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Saunderſon
<list>
                           <item>Ratliffe:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Sadler ſenior:</item>
                     <item>Iohn Stokes:</item>
                     <item>Richard Simmes, <hi>milend:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Smith
<list>
                           <item>Popley.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Samuel Soame</item>
                     <item>Iohn Swaine:</item>
                     <item>Robert Sheffield</item>
                     <item>Ieremy Swanley.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>I</head>
                     <pb n="62" facs="tcp:135289:34"/>
                     <item> Iohn ſweete, <hi>Bednall greene.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>George Smith
<list>
                           <item>White:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Smith <hi>his ſonn:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Anthony Skinner:</item>
                     <item>Paul Smith, <hi>White Chap:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Sadler iunor:</item>
                     <item>Nicholas Simondſon, <hi>Rat:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Samuel Sayers, <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>T</head>
                     <item>William Thorne
<list>
                           <item>Popley.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Thorne</item>
                     <item>Robert Thorne:</item>
                     <item>Edward Thickins
<list>
                           <item>White:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henry Tyler:</item>
                     <item>Morgan Thomas, <hi>Shorditch:</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henry Troutbeck
<list>
                           <item>Bow.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iohn Thorowgood</item>
                     <item>Stephen Trafford:</item>
                     <item>Richard Tiler
<list>
                           <item>Limehouſe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Peter Tailor.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>V</head>
                     <item>Thomas Vſher
<list>
                           <item>Hackney:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Valentine.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>W</head>
                     <item>Iohn Weſt
<list>
                           <item>Popley.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thomas Wats</item>
                     <item>Iohn Walden</item>
                     <item>Thomas Weſt.</item>
                     <item>Edmond White, <hi>Hackny.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Tho: Walker</item>
                     <item>Barthol: Walker</item>
                     <item>Eliz: Walker</item>
                     <item>Margaret Walker.
<list>
                           <item>Milend.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Emery Wilſon.</item>
                     <item>Eliz: Wilding <hi>wid.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Iane Wilding</item>
                     <item>Iane Willſon.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Watts.
<list>
                           <item>Ratliffe.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Wattkyns <hi>Wid.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Abraham Wakefield
<list>
                           <item>White</item>
                           <item>Chappell</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Thom. Wilſon <hi>et vx.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Laurence Wyneall.</item>
                     <item>Alice Williams:</item>
                     <item>Iohn Wilde, <hi>Shorditch.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Elizabeth walker
<list>
                           <item>Lime:</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Henry Walker</item>
                     <item>Iohn Walker</item>
                     <item>Mathew Woodcott</item>
                     <item>Anne Woodcott, <hi>vid.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Walter Whiting.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Whitebread
<list>
                           <item>Bow.</item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>Andrew Wilmer:</item>
                     <item>Iohn Wilkinſon:</item>
                     <item>Smith Wilkinſon:</item>
                     <item>Henry Watley:</item>
                     <item>Iohn Watley:</item>
                     <item>Iohn Wright:</item>
                     <item>Edward Wyborne:</item>
                     <item>Iohn Wyborne.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Y</head>
                     <item>Thomas Yardley, <hi>White Chap:</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="table_of_contents">
                  <pb n="63" facs="tcp:135289:34"/>
                  <head>
                     <hi>ANOTHER TA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>BLE ALPHABETI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>call, for the ready finding of the</hi> ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uerall customes, priuiledges and note-worthy <hi>mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, contained in this Booke.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <table>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>
                                 <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Cte</hi> or neglect of tennant for life or yeeres ſhall not preiudice thoſe in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder,</cell>
                           <cell>article 50.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Acte priuate</hi> of any tennants contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to theſe articles ſhall not extend to be abreach of cuſtomes to the hurt of the reſt,</cell>
                           <cell>article 51.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Admiſſion</hi> denied by the Lord,</cell>
                           <cell>ſee article 28.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>How lands diſcended are to be taken vp,</cell>
                           <cell>article 33. 34</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>See <hi>Diſſents,</hi> and <hi>Surrenders.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Amerciaments,</hi> the Lord may diſtreyne for, but not ſeiſe,</cell>
                           <cell>articles 53.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Annoyances,</hi> how to redreſſe,</cell>
                           <cell>ſee article 7.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Appearance:</hi> at two generall Courts yeerely,</cell>
                           <cell>article 3.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Fayling to appeare ſhall be amerced,</cell>
                           <cell>article 4.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Fayling at any Court (other then the two generall Courts) ſhall not bee amerced aboue foure pence</cell>
                           <cell>article 65.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Buildings</hi> hereafter to bee erected ſhall pay no other fines
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:135289:35"/> then in theſe articles,</cell>
                           <cell>art. 67.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Bylawes,</hi> may bee made by the <hi>Homage</hi> which ſhall binde the Tennants,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 63.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Courts,</hi> ſee <hi>Appearance.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Commons</hi> ſurcharged how to remedy,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 61. ſee <hi>Dri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uers.</hi>
                           </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Courteſie</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> none for men heere,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 11.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Clayme</hi> by diuers, and ſuite for Copyhold,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 31. 32. 57.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Chaunge</hi> of Lord, ſee <hi>Recognition.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Coheyres,</hi> ſee <hi>Diſcents</hi> and <hi>Partition.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Copyholders,</hi> may not pull downe houſen to ſet them vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on <hi>Freehold</hi> land,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 46. See <hi>Forfeitures.</hi>
                           </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Copyholders</hi> May breake and digge their grounds.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>May fell downe timber and woods.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>May ſuffer houſen to decay without forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>May loppe trees vpon the waſt before their houſen.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>May digge grauell, ſand, clay and loame vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the waſt to build or repaire,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 46. 47. See <hi>Leaſes.</hi>
                           </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Diſcents.</cell>
                           <cell>art. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>0. 12. 13. 14. 15. 16. 17. 18. 33.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Dower</hi> n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>ne,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 11.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Dryuers</hi> of the Common,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 60. 61. 62.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Enchroachments</hi> and annoyances how to redreſſe,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 7.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Eſcheate</hi> to the Lord for want of Heyre,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 10.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Eſtates</hi> of Inh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>ritance,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 1.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Fines</hi> due to the Lord vpon admiſsions,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 19. 26. 35. 67.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Forfeitures</hi> of Eſtate,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 48. 49.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Fees</hi> to the <hi>Homage,</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell>art: 56. 30.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Fees</hi> to the <hi>Steward,</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell>art: 66.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <pb n="6" facs="tcp:135289:35"/>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Gardian</hi> of the Heyre vnder age,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 33. 37.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Gauelkinde.</cell>
                           <cell>art: 12.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Homage,</hi> their charge and dutie, &amp;c.</cell>
                           <cell>art: 8. 9. 23. 31. 62. 63.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>What fees are due to the land,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 5. 6. 30.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Heyre</hi> not knowing what ſhall be done,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 10.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Headborough</hi> may take <hi>Surrenders</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell>art: 20. 22.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Laſt will</hi> and <hi>Teſtament.</hi> See <hi>Surrenders.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Leaſes,</hi> Tennants may let for thirty one yeeres and foure moneths in poſſeſsion from the making without Lyſence art: 38. but may not let for longer time vpon paine of forfeiture,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 48.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Leet:</hi> theſe tennants (beeing <hi>Reeues</hi>) are not to be charged with the <hi> Leet</hi> booke,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 42.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Marckes, Meares</hi> and <hi>Stakes,</hi> how to ſet betwixt Ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 59.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Partition,</hi> how to make betwixt Coheires, Ioint-tennants, and tennants in common,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 54.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Pownd</hi> of the Lord and cattell impounded how to deliuer,</cell>
                           <cell>article 55. 56. 58.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Quit-rents</hi> when to be paide, &amp;c.</cell>
                           <cell>art. 2. 36. 41.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Reeue,</hi> to take ſurrenders,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 20.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Surrenders taken by him when to be preſented.</cell>
                           <cell>22.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>How to be choſen,</cell>
                           <cell>40.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>How long to ſerue,</cell>
                           <cell>Ibidem.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>His fine for refuſing to ſerue,</cell>
                           <cell>Ibid.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>A new to be choſen vpon refuſall,</cell>
                           <cell>Ibid.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>The ſucceeding <hi>Reeue</hi> ſhall haue halfe of the fine of the former refuſing and detaine it in his accompt.</cell>
                           <cell>Ibid.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <pb n="66" facs="tcp:135289:36"/>
                        <row>
                           <cell>His lands ſhalbe ſeiſed for not paying rents and fines.</cell>
                           <cell>41.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>His forfeiture for not paying,</cell>
                           <cell>Ibid.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>He is not to anſweare any quit-rents vnleſſe hee knowe the tennant or the land.</cell>
                           <cell>Ibid.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Diſcharged of the <hi>Leet</hi> booke, Court Baron and dinners.</cell>
                           <cell>42.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Who may be choſen <hi>Reeue,</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell>43.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>What allowance and fees he ſhall haue for executing the office.</cell>
                           <cell>44.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>He muſt deliuer the Rentall to his ſucceſſor or ſhall be amerced.</cell>
                           <cell>45</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Recoueries</hi> to barre Intailes,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 64.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Recognition,</hi> money at the Caunge of the Lord,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 39.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Surrenders,</hi> how they are to be made,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 1. 19.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>How to bee taken before <hi>Headbrough</hi> or <hi>Reeue.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell>art: 20.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>How to be taked of women couert baron,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 21. 24</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>When ſurrenders are to be preſented,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 22. 25.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Surrenders made according to theſe articles are good,</cell>
                           <cell>27.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Surrenders to make the wife a Ioincture.</cell>
                           <cell>art: 29.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Thoſe to whoſe vſe landes are ſurrendred ought within three yeares after the preſentment to take them vp,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 34.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Stakes,</hi> marckes and meares betwixt tennants,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 59.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Stewards,</hi> fees particularly ſet downe,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 66.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <pb n="67" facs="tcp:135289:36"/>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Seuering,</hi> the Lord of the Mannor may not ſeuer any of theſe Copyholders to any perſon in fee,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 68.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Titles</hi> in controuerſie how to decide, ſee <hi>Claime.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Woemen</hi> couert baron, ſee <hi>Surrenders.</hi>
                           </cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Waſt, <hi>tennants for life or yeares making waſt, ſhall be fined by the</hi> Homage,</cell>
                           <cell>art: 52.</cell>
                        </row>
                     </table>
                  </p>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </body>
            <back>
               <div type="colophon">
                  <p>LONDON</p>
                  <p>Imprinted by WILLIAM IONES, with conſent of the ſaid right honourable THOMAS LORD WENTVVORTH, the fourth day of <hi>December.</hi> 1617.</p>
               </div>
            </back>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <body>
               <div type="memorandum">
                  <pb facs="tcp:135289:37"/>
                  <head>
                     <hi>Anno.</hi> 21. <hi>Jacobi Regis.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MEMORANDVM,</hi> that according to the former Couenaunts and agreements in this Booke conteyned, his ſaid Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip hath Honorably procured the Acte of Parliament, (ſo long deſired) for per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petuall eſtabliſhment of the ſayd Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes, benefits, and priuiledges, toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether with certaine expoſitions, enlarge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and explanations thereunto ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded. The copy of which Acte <hi>
                        <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>erbatim</hi> is as followeth. <hi>viz.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>An Acte</hi> for confirmation of the Copyhold eſtates and Cuſtomes of diuerſe Copy-holders, of the Mannors of <hi>Stepny</hi> and <hi>Hackney,</hi> according to cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teyne Indentures of agreement, and a Decree in the High Court of Chauncery, made betweene the <hi>Lord</hi> of the ſaid Mannors and the Copyholders.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="act">
                  <pb facs="tcp:135289:37"/>
                  <pb facs="tcp:135289:38"/>
                  <pb n="70" facs="tcp:135289:38" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <p>
                     <hi>IN moſt humble manner,</hi> doe beſeech your moſt Excellent <hi>Maieſtie,</hi> Your Highnes moſt humble and loyall ſubiect <hi>Thomas Lord Wentworth,</hi> Lord of the Mannors of <hi>Step<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney alias Stebenheath</hi> and <hi>Hackney,</hi> in Your Maieſties County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> and Your Highnes moſt humble and obedient ſubiects, <hi>Sir Iohn Iolles</hi> knight, and all the other Copi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders and cuſtomary Tenants of the ſayd Mannours, or of either of them, being par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties to certaine Indentures: bearing date the twentieth day of <hi>Iune,</hi> in the fifteenth yeare of your Highnes Raigne of <hi>England,</hi> made betweene the ſaid <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth,</hi> of the one parte, and the ſayd <hi>Sir Iohn Iolles</hi> &amp; divers other Copy-holders and Cuſtomary tenants of the ſaid Mannors in the ſame In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dentures named, of the other part, and all the now Copi-holders &amp; cuſtomary tenants of the ſaid Mannors and of either of them, claiming by from or vnder the ſaid Copy-hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders and Cuſtomary tenants parties to the ſaid Indentures. That whereas heretofore <note place="margin">
                        <hi>
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                              <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                           </gap> of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> Indenture o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> the</hi> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>0 <hi>of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>un<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>. ſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> 
                           <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                              <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi>
                     </note> diuers queſtions and Differences haue ari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen and beene moued, betweene your ſaid ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iect <hi>Tho: Lo: Wentworth,</hi> and the Copy-hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders and cuſtomary tenants of the ſayd Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors for and concerning the Copyhold lands, tenements hereditaments and eſtates of and within the ſame Mannors, and diuers cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes, benefits, priuiledges, diſcharges, &amp; other matters concerning the ſaid Copy-hold
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:135289:39" rendition="simple:additions"/> eſtates and premiſes: For appeaſing where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of and for preuention of the like and all others which in time to come might happen or grow betweene the ſaid Lord his heyres or aſſignes, and others Lords of the ſaid Mannors, and the ſaid Copy-holders and cuſtomary tenants named in the ſaid Indentures, and others te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of their tenements that ſhall be here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after. The ſame Indentures, together with certaine ſchedules thereunto annexed, were by the mutuall conſent and agreement of the ſaid Lord and tenants made ſealed deliuered and duly inrolled in Your Maieſties High court of Chauncery: In which ſaid Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures and ſchedules are conteined and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſed diuers cuſtomes, orders, immunities, diſcharges, benefits and priuiledges, by which the ſaid Copy-holders and cuſtomary tenants their heires and aſſignes, were and are to take, hold vſe and enioy, inherit, alien, demiſe and diſpoſe all and euery or any the landes meſſuages, tenements, cotages and hereditaments, which they, euery or any of them reſpectiuely then held claimed or enioy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, by force or pretence of any grant before that time made by Copy of Court Roll of the ſayd Mannors or either of them. And diuers other agreements, betweene the ſaid Lord, and Copy-holders or cuſtomary Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants, as in and by the ſaid Indentures and ſchedules more at large it doth and may ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare. Which ſaid Indentures and ſchedules, <note place="margin">
                        <hi>The Indenture of the</hi> 20: <hi>day of Iune was de<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>creed in Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cery. See Pag:</hi> 12.</note>
                     <pb n="72" facs="tcp:135289:39" rendition="simple:additions"/> and all the matters therein conteyned, in or ſhortly after Trinitie terme in the ſaid Fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth yeare of Your Highnes raigne, vpon a bill exhibited into Your Maieſties ſaid court of Chauncery by the ſaid Copy-holders a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the ſaid <hi>Lo: Wentworth,</hi> and vpon the ſame <hi>Lords</hi> anſwer thereunto, were duly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed, eſtabliſhed, and Decreed by the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree of your Maieſties ſaid court of Chaunce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry as by the ſaid bill, anſwere and Decree re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining of Record in the ſaid court it doth al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo appeare.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And whereas</hi> in the ſaid Indentures, one <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Recitall of the clauſe for ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of Leaſes. See Pag:</hi> 7. <hi>and Pag</hi> 39.</note> Clauſe or Article is conteined in theſe words following: And the ſaid <hi>Thomas Lord Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth,</hi> for him his heyres and aſſignes doeth by theſe preſents grant and agree, to and with the ſaid <hi>Sir Iohn Iolles</hi> and all other the perſons named to be parties to theſe preſents, and to and with the heyres and aſſignes of e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uery of them, that euery one of them, and eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of their heires and aſſignes ſhall and may freely hereafter from time to time grant, leaſe or demiſe by Deed or otherwiſe without li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence or copy of Court rolle, ſuch or ſo much of the lands, tenements, and hereditaments, or any part or parts thereof, of which they or any of them are Copy-holders or cuſtoma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry tenants, or reputed to be Copy-holders or cuſtomary tenants to ſuch perſon and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, and for ſuch terme and eſtate, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding Thirty and one yeares and foure mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monethes
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:135289:40"/> in poſſeſſion, from the time of the making of any ſuch grant or demiſe, as to the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> and euery or any of them reſpectiuely ſhall be thought fit or neceſſary, without any forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of eſtate, ſeizure, claime, diſturbance, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niall or impeachment of the ſaid <hi>Thomas Lo: Wentworth</hi> his heires or aſſignes, or any of his or their officers. So allwayes that ſuch grants, leaſe and leaſes ſo to be made, be at the firſt or ſecond generall court for the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor whereof the landes or tenements ſo hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pening to be granted leaſed or demiſed are parcell to be holden next after the making thereof be publiſhed in open Court of that Mannor before the Homage there, and a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>membrance thereof to be required to be made in the Rolles of the ſame court for the date terme and quantity of lands cottages or tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments ſo granted leaſed or demiſed. Which remembrance the ſaid <hi>Thomas</hi> Lord <hi>Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth</hi> couenanteth and granteth for him his heires &amp; aſſignes, to &amp; with the ſaid Sir <hi>Iohn Iolles</hi> and all other the ſaid perſons named parties to theſe preſents, and their and eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of their heires and aſſignes vpon the ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of a certainty thereof in writing to the Steward or Deputy Steward of that man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, for the time then being, together with ſix pence of lawfull money of England for the entring thereof, ſhall be in the court rolles of that Mannor duly and in conuenient time and without delay inrolled, and a note there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:135289:40" rendition="simple:additions"/> deliuered by the Steward for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or his Deputy, to the party ſo leaſing or any for him, without any other conſideration fee or reward to be giuen or paid for the ſame.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And in the ſaid</hi> Schedules one other article <note place="margin">
                        <hi>Recitall of the</hi> 38 <hi>article ſee Pag:</hi> 39.</note> to the like effect is conteyned in theſe wordes following. Item, if any perſon or perſons be diſpoſed to let his or their cuſtomary lands or tenements, to any other perſon or perſons and to their executors and aſſignes for the terme of one and thirty yeares or leſſe, the ſame perſon or perſons haue and ſhall haue full power and authority to ſet or let to farme his or their copy-hold, landes or tenements to any perſon or perſons their executors admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtrators and aſſignes, for the terme of one and thirty yeares and foure monethes or leſſe in poſſeſſion from the time of the making there of by writing without any licence to him or them to be granted, and without paying any fine to the Lord, or incurring any forfeiture or ſeizure of or for the ſame: So as the ſame leaſe doe not exceed one and thirty yeares and foure monethes from the time of the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king thereof: But ſuch leaſe is and ought to be preſented to the Homage of the Mannor whereof the landes or tenements ſo leaſed, are held within one yeare after the making thereof: Or elſe the ſame leaſe ſo made and not preſented as is aforeſaid ſhall bee void &amp; of none effect, as in and by the ſaid Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures and Schedules appeareth. The intent
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:135289:41" rendition="simple:additions"/> and true meaning of which ſaid Indentures, <note place="margin">
                        <hi>The intent of the Clauſe and Article was to make good all leaſes, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding</hi> 31. <hi>yeares and</hi> 4. <hi>monethes.</hi>
                     </note> and of all and euery the ſaid parties thereunto was and now is: That the ſaid clauſes and articles ſhould &amp; ſhall be taken and conſtrued to be to confirme, allow, and make good all &amp; euery leaſes and grants made and to be made and entred as aforeſaid, although any ſuch leaſe or grant, leaſes or grants, hath or haue beene or ſhall be made or limited to commence or beginne from after or at any day or time after the making or date thereof ſo as the whole terme granted or to be granted in or by ſuch leaſe or grant leaſes or grants, together with the time incurred or to to incurre from the day of the date or making thereof, vntill the day or time limited or to be limited for the beginning or commencement thereof do not exceed Thirty and one yeares and foure monethes in the whole.</p>
                  <p>And the ſaid ſeuerall limitations and prouiſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons conteyned in the ſaid firſt recited clauſe or article for or concerning ſuch publiſhing of the ſaid leaſes or grants, and ſuch requiring of a remembrance thereof to be made in the ſaid rolles, and ſuch tender of the Certainty there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of inwriting, and of the ſaid ſix pence for the entry thereof as in and by the ſame clauſe or article is preſcribed or metioned. And the ſaid limitation or prouiſion conteyned in the ſaid laſt recited clauſe or article for or concerning ſuch preſenting of ſuch leaſes to the ſaid Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage as in and by the ſame laſt recited clauſe
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:135289:41" rendition="simple:additions"/> or article is preſcribed or mentioned were inſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted into the ſayd ſeuerall clauſes or articles, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectiuely as is aforeſaid: To the onely intent <note place="margin">And to prevent frauds &amp;c.</note> and purpoſe to preuent frauds to be vſed by any Copy-holders of the ſaid Mannors or either of them in letting his or their Copy-hold lands or tenements for yeares at a ſmall rent or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, and afterwardes ſurrendring the ſame to the vſe of ſome other perſon or perſons for mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney or other conſiderations, as if it were in poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion and not charged with any ſuch Leaſe or grant: But not with any purpoſe, that the neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect or omiſſion of publiſhing any ſuch Leaſe or <note place="margin">But not to giue any forfeictur to the Lord, for neglect.</note> grant in the court of the ſaid Mannors or either of them, or of any requeſt to be made for any ſuch remembrance thereof to be made in the Rolles of the ſaid Court or of the tendring of a certainty of any ſuch leaſe in writing to the ſaid Steward or Deputy Steward of any of the ſaid Mannors, or of the ſaid ſix pence for entry thereof or of the preſenting thereof to the ſayd Homage as in and by the ſaid recited clauſes or articles is limited or mentioned, ſhould giue or be any cauſe of forfeiture or ſeizure of any of the ſaid copyhold premiſſes ſo to be leaſed or grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, to the Lord of the ſaid Mannors or either of them for the time being, but onely to make ſuch Leaſes and Grantes, for and in reſpect of ſuch neglect or omiſſion as is aforeſaid vtterly voyd &amp; of no e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ect, which ſaid intent &amp; true meaning of the ſaid Indentures and of the ſaid parties thereunto is teſtified, agreed and declared in
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:135289:42" rendition="simple:additions"/> and by certaine other Indentures made be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tweene the ſaid parties to the ſaid firſt recited Indentures, and bearing date the laſt day of <note place="margin">
                        <hi>The Indentures of the</hi> 30: <hi>of Iune.</hi>
                     </note> 
                     <hi>Iune</hi> in the ſaid Fifteenth yeare of your Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Raigne. <hi>May it therefore</hi> pleaſe Your moſt excellent Maieſty, at the humble ſuite of your ſaid ſubiects, and for the ſetling of perpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tua<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>l peace and quietneſſe amongſt them in and concerning the premiſſes: That it may be enac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by your highneſſe with the aſſent of the Lordes ſpirituall and temporall, and the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons in this preſent <hi>Parliament</hi> Aſſembled, and be it enacted by the Authority of the ſame: That the making of any Leaſe or grant, leaſes or grants ſithence the making of the ſaid firſt mentioned Indentures, or of any Leaſe or <note place="margin">
                        <hi>The Act that Leaſes may be let for</hi> 31: <hi>yeares</hi> 4. <hi>mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neths from the making, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out forfeiture.</hi>
                     </note> grant, leaſes or grants at any time hereafter to be made for any terme or tearmes of yeares not exceeding one and thirty yeares and foure monethes from the making or Date thereof by any the Copy-holders or Cuſtomary Tenants parties to the ſaid firſt mentioned Indentures their heires or aſſignes, or others that hereaf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter ſhall be Tenements by Copy of Court Boll or Cuſtomary Tenants of any of the Landes or Tenements that were any of the ſaid per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons named to bee parties at the time of the making of the ſaid firſt mencioned Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, from time to time ſhall not be any forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, or cauſe of forfeiture, or ſeizure, to or for the Lord of the ſaid Mannors, or either of them for the time being, or to or for any other perſon or perſons lawfully clayming
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:135289:42" rendition="simple:additions"/> from by or vnder the ſame Lord or Lords all<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though ſuch Leaſe leaſes or grants hath beene or ſhall be made without any licence of the Lord of the ſaid Mannors or either of them or hath not beene or ſhall not be publiſhed in the Court of the ſame Mannors or either of them, and all<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though no requeſt hath beene or ſhall be made for any remembrance thereof to be made in the Rolles of the ſaid Court, or any ſuch tender of a certainty of any ſuch leaſe or grant, leaſes or grants, or of ſix pence or any other ſumme for entry thereof, and although any ſuch Leaſe or grant, leaſes or grants hath not or haue not beene or ſhall not bee preſented to the ſaid Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage as in and by the ſaid clauſes or articles is preſcribed or mentioned. And although any ſuch Leaſe or grant, leaſes or grants hath or haue beene or ſhall bee made or limited to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mence or beginne from after or at any day or time after the making or date thereof, ſo as the whole terme granted or to be granted in or by ſuch Leaſe or grant together with the time in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curred or to incurre from the day of the date or making thereof vntill the day or time limited or to be limited for the begining or commence<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment thereof do not exceed, Thirty one yeares and foure monethes in the whole, and that the neglect or omiſſion of any ſuch publiſhing, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſting, tendring, or preſenting as is afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid neither is nor ſhall bee any forfeiture or cauſe of forfeiture or ſeizure of the Landes or Tenements ſo Leaſed or to be leaſed or grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:135289:43" rendition="simple:additions"/> or any of them: But if any ſuch neglect or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion hath beene or at any time hereafter ſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>be, <note place="margin">
                        <hi>But the Leaſes to be voyd, if they be not pre<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſented at the firſt or</hi> 2. <hi>gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall Court next following.</hi>
                     </note> then euery ſuch Leaſe of or concerning the which ſuch neglect or omiſſion hath beene or ſhall bee had, ſhall be vtterly voyd and of no effect.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And be it further</hi> enacted by the authority of <note place="margin">Both the Inde<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                        <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Schedules, Decree, &amp; pre<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſent explanati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the ſaid clauſe &amp; Art. enacted to ſta<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>d foreuer.</note> this preſent Parliament: That aſwell the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid two clauſes or Articles herein perticu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lerly recited with ſuch alteration or addition, and ſo explaned, conſtrued, and enlarged as is aforeſaid: As alſo all and euery other the Clau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, Articles, Agreements and matters in the ſaid ſeuerall Indentures, Schedules, and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree and euery or any of them conteyned ſhall be ratefied, allowed, and confirmed by the autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of this preſent Parliament, and that the ſame ſeuerall Indentures, Schedules, and Decree ſo explained, confirmed and enlarged, as is aforeſaid: and euery of them ſhall bee of force to bind and conclude, all and euery the ſaid parties thereunto or to any of them, and their and euery of their heires executors admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtrators and aſſignes, and all and euery per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon and perſons clayming or which ſhall claime from by or vnder them or any of them in all thinges, according to the purport effect and true meaning of the ſame ſeuerall Indentures, Schedules, and Decree, and of euery of them, and of this preſent Act: And that the ſame ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uerall Indentures, Schedules and Decree, and euery of them and euery Clauſe, Article,
<pb n="80" facs="tcp:135289:43" rendition="simple:additions"/> and ſentence in them and euery or any of them conteined with ſuch alteration &amp; enlargments, and ſo explained as is aforeſaid, ſhall for euer from and after the making of the ſame Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, Schedules, and Decree, ſtand bee and remaine, and ſhall be adiudged and taken to ſtand and be of ſuch and the ſame force and ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect to all intents and purpoſes as if the ſame ſeuerall Indentures, Schedules and Decree, ſo explained, conſtrued and enlarged, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid and euery of them and euery Clauſe, Article and ſentence in euery of them conteyned were ſpecially and perticulerly expreſſed and enacted by the Authority of this preſent Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And whereas</hi> ſithence the making of the ſaid <note place="margin">Thoſe which haue compoun<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ded ſince the firſt Indenture; ſhall enioy the like benefite as the former.</note> firſt mentioned Indentures Your moſt humble Subiects, <hi>Sir Thomas Hardreſſe</hi> Knight, <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Catcher</hi> ſonne of <hi>Thomas Catcher</hi> mony<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, <hi>Iohn Wright</hi> butcher, <hi>Thomas Pynnocke, Elizabeth Hide, Dorithy Hide</hi> daughter of <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Hide, Walter Whiting</hi> mariner, <hi>Giles Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trick</hi> and <hi>Sibell</hi> his wife, <hi>Michaell Merrioll, Iohn Bigate, Anne Ryland</hi> late the wife of <hi>William Haggis, Thomas Wilſon</hi> gentleman, and <hi>Kathe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rine</hi> his wife, <hi>Iohn Crane, Giles de Bude, Sara Hill, Conſtance Clarke, Mary Simondſon, Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Denham, Samuell Crowther, Iohn Crow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, Ioſeph Crowther, Mary Tineſty, Thomas Ieffery, George Needham, William Locke, Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Pierce</hi> his heyres, <hi>Thomas Damport</hi> gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, <hi>Richard Bradley, Thomas Paramore</hi> Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qtuer,
<pb facs="tcp:135289:44" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                        <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <pb facs="tcp:135289:44" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                        <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <pb n="81" facs="tcp:135289:45" rendition="simple:additions"/> 
                     <hi>Iohn Robothom</hi> gentleman, <hi>Richard Alſop, Iohn Vaſſoll, William Speering, George Speering, Walter Whiting, Richard Para<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>more, Iohn Robinſon, Griffine Ellis, Ioſeph Thornton, Beniamine Thornton, Tobias Thorn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton, Mathew Graues, William Philips</hi> Mari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, <hi>IOHN GALE</hi> gentleman, <hi>WILLIAM GALE</hi> gentleman, <hi>HYMFRY WESTVVOOD, GEORGE SMITH</hi> gentleman, <hi>CHRISTOPHER POTKIN, EDVVARD BVRLEY, FELIX WIL<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>SON</hi> gentleman, and <hi>ANNE</hi> his wife, <hi>AR<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>THVR WINGHAM, RICHARD WINGHAM</hi> and <hi>THOMAS WINGHAM</hi> her <hi>ſonnes, WIL<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>LIAM DOVE</hi> gentleman <hi>Anne</hi> his wife, and <hi>IOHN PEASE</hi> her ſonne, <hi>WILLIAM CHAP<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>PELL</hi> and <hi>HENRY IOHNSON</hi> Brewer, <hi>RO<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>BERT KEALE<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </hi> gentleman, <hi>THOMAS CHAP<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>MAN IOANE</hi> his wife, <hi>DANIELL BASSANO, IOHN HODGSON, HELKIAH READE, COR<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>NELIVS GODFREY, THOMAS THORNTON, PHILLIP IOYCE</hi> and <hi>ELIZABETH</hi> his wife, <hi>THOMAS THREDDER,</hi> being Copy-holders and Cuſtomary Tennants of Diuerſe meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuages, Landes, and Tenements, ſome o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> them being percell of or within the ſayd <hi>Man nor</hi> of <hi>Stepney alias Stebenheath,</hi> and the reſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>due thereof being parcell of or within the ſaid Mannor of <hi>Hackney,</hi> haue likewiſe ſithence the ſayd firſt mencioned Indentures com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded, and agreed with Your ſaid Subiect <hi>Thomas Lord Wentworth,</hi> to haue and enioy to them, their Heires and Aſſignes, ſuch the
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:135289:45"/> ſame and the like Cuſtomes, Orders Immu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nities, diſcharges, benefits and Priuiledges, of in for and concerning All the Meſſuages, landes, Tenements, and Hereditaments, which they the ſaid Copy-holders and cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mary Tenants laſt before named and euery or any of them reſpectiuely do now hold claime or enioy, by force or pretence of any grant here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tofore made by Copy of Court Roll of the ſaid ſeuerall Mannors, or either of them, as the ſaid <hi>Sir Iohn Iolles</hi> and the reſt of the ſaid Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyholders being parties or named parties to the ſaid ſeuerall Indentures, their heires and aſſignes by the intent and true meaning of the ſaid ſeuerall Indentures Schedules and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree, and of this preſent Act, haue and enioy, or are to haue and enioy of in for or concerning their ſaid ſeuerall Copyhold meſſuages, lands Tenements and Herediraments. It may further pleaſe Your moſt excellent Maieſty for the like ſetling of a continuall peace be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tweene Your ſaid ſubiects <hi>Thomas Lord Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth</hi> and the ſaid <hi>Sir Thomas Hardreſſe</hi> knight and other the laſt named Copy-holders afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid: That it may be further enacted by Your Highnes with the aſſent of the Lords Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rituall and Temporall and the Commons in this preſent Parliament aſſembled.</p>
                  <p>And be it enacted by the authority of the ſame Parliament: That aſwell the ſaid ſeuerall Indentures Schedules and Decree, and eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:135289:46" rendition="simple:additions"/> of them with ſuch expoſition, enlargement, &amp; explanation as aforeſaid: As alſo this preſent Act of Parliament, ſhall extend vnto and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehend, and ſhall be taken and adiudged to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend vnto and comprehend the ſaid <hi>Sir Thomas Hardreſſe</hi> Knight and other Copy-holders a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid before mentioned to haue compounded and agreed with the ſaid <hi>Lo: Wentworth,</hi> ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thence the making of the ſaid firſt mentioned Indentures for and concerning all the Meſſua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges landes Tenements and Hereditaments which they the ſaid laſt mencioned Copy-hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders or any of them reſpectiuely do now hold, claime or enioy by force or pretence of any grant by copy of Court Roll of the ſaid Mannors or either of them, as fully and amply, and in as large and beneficiall manner, to all intents and purpoſes, as if the ſame laſt mentioned Copy-holders and euery of them had beene parties and party to the ſaid ſeuerall Indentures and either of them, and as if their ſaid ſeuerall Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py-hold Meſſuages lands Tenements and Hereditaments had beene by apert and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſize words conteined or compriſed in the ſaid ſeuerall Indentures Schedules and Decree. and in this preſent Act of Parliament, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uery of them: And that the ſaid laſt mentioned Copyholders and euery of them, and the heires executors adminiſtrators &amp; aſſignes of them and euery of them, and all and euery perſon and perſons clayming or which ſhall claime from by or vnder them or any of them ſhall and
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:135289:46" rendition="simple:additions"/> may foreuer heereafter, haue take an enioye ſuch the like and the ſame benefite profit and aduantage by the ſayd ſeuerall Indentures, Schedules, and Decree of, for, and concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, all and euery the ſaid Meſſuages and Premiſes, which they and euery or any of them reſpectiuely doe hold, claime, or enioy by force or pretence of any graunt, by Copy of Court Roll of the ſayd Mannors: or either of them, and as fully and amply, as the ſayd parties: to the ſayd ſeuerall Indentures, their Heires and Aſſignes, by the intent and true meaning, of the ſayd ſeuerall Indentures, Se edules and Decree, and of this preſent Act may haue take or enioy, or are or ought to haue, take or enioy.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Prouided</hi> allwayes, that this Act or any <note place="margin">None but thoſe who haue compounded, ſhall haue be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit by this Act.</note> thing therein conteyned: ſhall not extend or be any wiſe conſtrued, or expounded, to extend to any Copy-holders, other then ſuch as are na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med parties to the ſayd firſt recited Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, and the Heires, Executors, Adminiſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors and Aſſignes, of euery of them, and all and euery perſon, and perſons, lawfully claim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or which ſhall claime, from, by, or vnder them: or any of them, And other then ſuch Copy-holders who are before named in this Act, and who haue ſithence compounded, and agreed with the ſayd <hi>Thom. Lord Wentworth,</hi> as is aforeſayd, and their Heyres. Executors, Adminiſtrators or Aſſignes, and all and eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry perſon and perſons, lawfully clayming: or
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:135289:47" rendition="simple:additions"/> which ſhall clayme, from by or vnder them, or any of them. Neither ſhall this Act extend to <note place="margin">N<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> they, but for the Lands &amp;c, for which they compoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded.</note> any copyhold, meſſuages, Cottages, landes, tenements or Hereditaments, other then ſuch, whereof the ſayd Copyholders or others, clay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming vnder them: were reſpectiuely ſeized or poſſeſſed at the times of their ſayd ſeuerall and reſpectiue agreements, for or concerning the ſame: with the ſaid Lord, or now are vnder the ſayd agreements, ſeized or poſſeſſed, as aforeſaid. But this Acte ſhall extend to all &amp; euery the Copy-hold meſſuages, Cottages, lands Tenements, and Hereditaments, wher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the ſayd Copy-holders or any others claym<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing vnder them, were reſpectiuely ſeized, or poſſeſſed at the times of theſe ſeuerall and reſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pectiue agreements, for, or concerning the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes, with the ſayd Lord, or now are vnder the ſayd agreements, ſeized or poſſeſſed as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid. <hi>Sauing Neuertheleſſe</hi> to Your High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes, <note place="margin">Sauing to the K. &amp; all other their Perticular rights.</note> Your Heyres and Succeſſors, and to all and euery perſon and perſons, bodyes Politi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>que and Corporate, their Heires and Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, other then the ſaid <hi>Lord Wentworth,</hi> his Heires and Aſſignes, and all and euery per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon and Perſons lawfully clayming from, by, or vnder them, or any of them, and other then the ſayd parties to the ſayd ſeuerall Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures: and the ſaid Copyholders before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned to haue compounded with the ſaid now <hi>Lord Wentworth,</hi> and euery of them, and the Heires and Aſſignes of euery of them, and all
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:135289:47"/> and euery perſon and perſons lawfully claym<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from, by, or vnder them, or any of them. All ſuch actions, eſtates, poſſeſſions, rights, Titles, Intereſts, Seruices, Rents, and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maunds, Profitts, commodities and aduanta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tages whatſoeuer, as they or any of them, haue, ſhall, may, or ought to haue of, in to, or out of all, or any of the Premiſſes, in ſuch and the ſame eſtate, degree, plight, manner and forme to all intents and purpoſes, as if this Acte had neuer ben had or made.</p>
               </div>
            </body>
            <back>
               <div type="table_of_contents">
                  <head>The Contents of this Act.</head>
                  <p>
                     <table>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Leaſes may bee let for thirty one yeares and foure monethes from the making without forfeiture<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                           </cell>
                           <cell>
                              <hi>Pag.</hi> 77.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>But the Leaſes ſhall bee voide, if the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed rule, be not obſerued.</cell>
                           <cell>79.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <pb n="87" facs="tcp:135289:48"/>
                        <row>
                           <cell>The Indentures of the twentieth and thirtieth of <hi>Iune. Anno</hi> 15. <hi>Iacobi Regis:</hi> with the Schedules, and the Decree in Chauncery, with the preſent explana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the thirty eight article are all enacted to ſtand firme for euer.</cell>
                           <cell>79.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Thoſe which haue compounded ſince the firſt Indentures, ſhall inioy the like benefit, as the former.</cell>
                           <cell>80.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>None but thoſe who haue compounded, ſhall reape any benefit by this Act.</cell>
                           <cell>84.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Nor they but only for the Lands &amp;c, for which they haue compounded.</cell>
                           <cell>85.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Sauing to Kings Maieſtie, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers their particular rights.</cell>
                           <cell>85.</cell>
                        </row>
                     </table>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="list_of_tenants">
                  <head>An Alphabeticall Table of the names of the Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pyhold Tenants which haue compounded ſince the firſt Indentures, and are inabled by this Act, to reape the like benefit with the former.</head>
                  <list>
                     <head>A</head>
                     <item>Richard Alſop.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>B</head>
                     <item>Iohn Bigate.</item>
                     <item>Giles de Bude.</item>
                     <item>Richard Bradley.</item>
                     <item>Edward Burley.</item>
                     <item>Daniell Baſſano,</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>C</head>
                     <item>Richard Catcher ſonne</item>
                     <item>o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Tho: Catcher monier.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Crane.</item>
                     <item>Conſtance Clarckes</item>
                     <item>Samuell Crowther,</item>
                     <item>William Chappell.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Chapman and Ioane his wife.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>D.</head>
                     <item>Thomas Denham.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Damport, Gent.</item>
                     <item>William Doue Gent. and Anne his wife.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>E.</head>
                     <item>Griffin Ellis.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>G.</head>
                     <item>Mathew Graues.</item>
                     <pb n="88" facs="tcp:135289:48"/>
                     <item> Iohn Gale Gent.</item>
                     <item>Cornelius Godfrey.</item>
                     <item>William Gale Gent.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>H.</head>
                     <item>Sir Thomas Hardreſſe K.</item>
                     <item>Elizabeth Hide.</item>
                     <item>Dorothie Hide.</item>
                     <item>Sara Hill.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Hodgſon.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>I.</head>
                     <item>Thomas Ieffery.</item>
                     <item>Henry Iohnſon Brewer.</item>
                     <item>Phillip Ioice, and Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth his wife.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>K.</head>
                     <item>Robert Keale Gent.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>L.</head>
                     <item>William Lock.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>M.</head>
                     <item>Michaell Merrioll.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>N.</head>
                     <item>George Needham.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>P.</head>
                     <item>Thomas Pynnock.</item>
                     <item>Giles Patricke and Sibell his wife.</item>
                     <item>Peter Piers his heires.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Paramore Eſqu.</item>
                     <item>Richard Paramore.</item>
                     <item>Willi: Phillips Mariner.</item>
                     <item>Chriſtopher Potkin.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Peaſe.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>R.</head>
                     <item>Anne Ryland.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Robotham Gent.</item>
                     <item>Iohn Robinſon.</item>
                     <item>Helkiah Reade.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>S.</head>
                     <item>Mary Symonſon.</item>
                     <item>William Speering.</item>
                     <item>George Speering.</item>
                     <item>George Smith Gent.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>T</head>
                     <item>Mary Tineſtey.</item>
                     <item>Ioſeph Thornton.</item>
                     <item>Beniamin Thornton.</item>
                     <item>Tobias Thornton.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Thornton.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Thredder.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>V</head>
                     <item>Iohn Vaſſoll.</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>W</head>
                     <item>Iohn Wright Butcher.</item>
                     <item>Walter Whiting Mariner.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Wilſon Gent, &amp; Katherine his wife.</item>
                     <item>Walter Whiting.</item>
                     <item>Humphfry Weſtwood.</item>
                     <item>Felix Wilſon Gent, and Anne his wife.</item>
                     <item>Arthur Wingham.</item>
                     <item>Richard Wingham.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Wingham. her ſonnes.</item>
                  </list>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </back>
         </text>
      </group>
   </text>
</TEI>
